<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Inquirer News Syndication</title>
	<atom:link href="https://dotnetapp.inq.ph/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://dotnetapp.inq.ph</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:44:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	4	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Korean Olympic shooter Kim Ye-ji treated in hospital after fainting</title>
		<link>https://sports.inquirer.net/579454/korean-olympic-shooter-kim-ye-ji-treated-in-hospital-after-fainting</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:44:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sports.inquirer.net/579454/korean-olympic-shooter-kim-ye-ji-treated-in-hospital-after-fainting</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>South Korean pistol shooter Kim Ye-ji, who gained global fame for her confidence and style during the Paris Olympics, was taken to a hospital after fainting during a press conference, officials said Friday.</p>
<p>The 31-year-old won silver in the women&#8217;s 10-meter air pistol event in Paris last week, and her ultra-calm demeanor, combined with her wire-rimmed shooting glasses and baseball cap, made her a worldwide online sensation &#8212; drawing praise from celebrities such as X owner Elon Musk.</p>
<p>The star shooter suddenly collapsed while speaking to reporters in a southern town on Friday and was sent to hospital, local officials said.</p>
<div class="lSfe4c r5bEn aI5QMe">
<div class="SoAPf">
<div class="n0jPhd ynAwRc MBeuO nDgy9d" role="heading" aria-level="3"><strong>READ: <a href="https://sports.inquirer.net/577259/korean-shooter-kim-ye-jis-cool-aura-captivates-social-media">Korean shooter Kim Ye-ji’s cool aura captivates social media</a></strong></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>A spokesman for Imsil County told AFP that Kim had &#8220;recovered&#8221; after the incident and has since been transferred to a general hospital in Jeonju, approximately 29 kilometers (18 miles) north of Imsil.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have been informed by emergency aid workers that she does not require serious treatment,&#8221; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Another official said she would undergo a medical check-up.</p>

<p>Her coach, Kwak Min-su, told local reporters that Kim had no underlying health issues and had been dealing with &#8220;accumulated fatigue&#8221; along with a very hectic schedule since mid-July.</p>
<div class="lSfe4c r5bEn aI5QMe">
<div class="SoAPf">
<div class="n0jPhd ynAwRc MBeuO nDgy9d" role="heading" aria-level="3"><strong>READ: <a href="https://sports.inquirer.net/577566/who-is-yusuf-dikec-the-turkish-shooter-at-paris-olympics">Who is Yusuf Dikec, the Turkish shooter at Paris Olympics</a></strong></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Since her silver-medal win, a short clip showing Kim &#8212; which in fact shows her at the Baku World Cup in May, not Paris &#8212; has gone viral, spawning fan art as well as multiple edits setting the clip to K-pop music, and endless memes, including some discussing her unique &#8220;aura&#8221;.</p>
<p>Despite being a strong favorite for gold in the 25-metre event, an error during the qualifying round &#8212; failing to take her shot within the required three-second window and scoring zero &#8212; prevented her from advancing to the finals.</p>
<p>She has since apologized for making a &#8220;big mistake&#8221; and &#8220;disappointing&#8221; her fans.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[Associated Press]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Paris Olympics]]></category>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:44:51 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>17 Filipino seafarers safe after recent Houthi rebels’ attack</title>
		<link>https://globalnation.inquirer.net/244921/17-filipino-seafarers-safe-after-recent-houthi-rebels-attack</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://globalnation.inquirer.net/244921/17-filipino-seafarers-safe-after-recent-houthi-rebels-attack</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>MANILA, Philippines – The Department of Migrant Workers (DMW) on Friday confirmed that all 17 Filipino seafarers aboard a Liberian-flagged container vessel were safe following the recent attack by Houthi rebels while traversing the Gulf of Aden.</p>
<p>In a press release, the DMW said that MV Groton with 19 crew members on board was hit with a ballistic missile last August 3.</p>
<p>The DMW said it would continue to monitor the situation.</p>
<p>It added that it was ready to assist the seafarers and their families.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>READ: <a href="https://globalnation.inquirer.net/239794/21-filipino-seafarers-rescued-from-houthi-hit-ship-arrive-in-ph#ixzz8iOGqY9bm">21 Filipino seafarers rescued from Houthi-hit ship arrive in PH</a></strong></p>
<p>“The Department also reminds Filipino seafarers that they have the right to refuse sailing in High-risk and War-like zones,” such as the Red Sea and the Gulf of Aden.</p>
<p>“Seafarers may inform the DMW of their conditions or submit their Confirmation of Refusal to traverse the Red Sea or Gulf of Aden, and/or to other High-risk and War-like zones at sbhighrisk@dmw.gov.ph.,” the press release added.</p>
<p>The department also reiterated its call for shipowners to divert from the Red Sea and the Gulf of Aden, stating that it will strictly enforce Department Order No. 3 series of 2024 which prohibits the deployment of Filipino seafarers on board ships that have already been attacked on designated High-risk and War-like zones.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>READ: <a href="https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1944784/dmw-logs-all-time-high-deployment-of-filipino-seafarers-in-2023#ixzz8iOGwsep8">DMW logs ‘all-time high’ deployment of Filipino seafarers in 2023</a></strong></p>
<p>MV Groton sustained minor damages after it was attacked 60 nautical miles off Yemen on its way to Jeddah, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>It diverted its course and is now docked at the port of Djibouti for evaluation.</p>
<p>The ship&#8217;s operator, Cornbulk Shipmanagement Corporation, said no oil leakages or entry of water have been observed.</p>
<p>International reports stated that the Houthi rebels claimed responsibility for the attack.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[Philippine News Agency]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[GlobalNation]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Filipino seafarersHouthi Rebels]]></category>
<ArticleSlug><![CDATA[Global Pinoy]]></ArticleSlug>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:35:33 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Serbia&#8217;s hot shooting not enough vs Steph Curry, Team USA</title>
		<link>https://sports.inquirer.net/579449/serbias-hot-shooting-not-enough-vs-steph-curry-team-usa</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:33:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sports.inquirer.net/579449/serbias-hot-shooting-not-enough-vs-steph-curry-team-usa</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>PARIS — Trailing and with its streak of four consecutive Olympic gold medals in danger, Team USA was trying desperately to mount a semifinal comeback.</p>
<p>There was only one problem — Serbia kept making 3-pointers.</p>
<p>And making them. And making them.</p>
<p>The Paris Olympics semifinal showdown between the four-time defending gold medal-winning Team USA and Serbia turned into a 3-point shooting contest.</p>
<p class="LC20lb MBeuO DKV0Md"><strong>READ: <a href="https://sports.inquirer.net/579393/paris-olympics-usa-beats-serbia-to-face-france-for-mens-basketball-gold">Team USA beats Serbia, faces France for men&#8217;s basketball gold</a></strong></p>
<p>Serbia nearly prevailed. And, in doing so, came within a late flurry of stunning the title favorites before losing 95-91, almost denying one of the most star-laden teams since the 1992 Dream Team a chance of another gold.</p>
<p>“I still believe that we could have won this game, a couple of possessions, a call goes our way, a couple of shots,&#8221; Serbia&#8217;s Bogdan Bogdanovic said. &#8220;But that is basketball. You should be proud even if you lose a game like this.”</p>
<p>Serbia made 15 of 39 shots from beyond the arc, compared with 16 of 32 by the Americans. It almost nullified nine 3-point makes by Stephen Curry — the NBA’s all-time leader in 3-point makes — who finished with 36 points.</p>
<p>It contributed to Serbia&#8217;s big leads during the game, which stretched to as much as 17 points.</p>
<p>“They came out and hit some amazingly tough shots in the first half,” Curry said. “You have to credit to them, they&#8217;re a really good team. &#8230; but to come back the way we did, like, I&#8217;ve seen a lot of Team USA basketball and that was a special one.”</p>
<p class="LC20lb MBeuO DKV0Md"><strong>READ: <a href="https://sports.inquirer.net/579414/durant-hails-god-like-steph-curry-after-heroics-for-team-usa">Durant hails &#8216;God-like&#8217; Steph Curry after heroics for Team USA</a></strong></p>
<div class="notranslate HGLrXd NJjxre iUh30 ojE3Fb">
<div class="q0vns">

</div>
</div>
<p>It left the Serbian players stunned as they shook hands after the game. Bogdanovic, who had 20 points including three 3-pointers, was in tears. At one point he pulled his jersey over his head and crouched to the ground as teammates consoled him.</p>
<p>Curry&#8217;s efforts left his teammates in awe of what they&#8217;ve seen so many nights on NBA floors, travel to the international level.</p>
<p>“Steph? Man, that was a godlike performance,&#8221; Kevin Durant said. &#8220;That was tough. It felt like he was struggling throughout the whole tournament. We always said: Each night it’ll be somebody different. Tonight, he showed up in a way that, man, God was with him tonight. He was with us tonight, through Steph.”</p>
<p class="LC20lb MBeuO DKV0Md">READ: <a href="https://sports.inquirer.net/578962/kevin-durant-becomes-team-usa-career-scoring-leader-in-olympics"><strong>Kevin Durant becomes Team USA scoring leader in Olympics</strong></a></p>
<p>The ultimate example of Serbia’s hot night from deep may have been late in the third quarter. The U.S. chopped what had been a 17-point deficit to 67-61.</p>
<p>Serbia responded with a 3 from Vasilije Micic. Then, after a pair of free throws by Marko Guduric and a miss by the U.S., Gurduric got free and drained another 3 and was fouled.</p>
<p>He hit the ensuing free throw to complete the four-point play.</p>
<p>The Serbians didn’t show any fear in the first half, shooting 54% from the field, including 10 of 19 from the 3-point line.</p>
<p>It canceled a half that saw Curry catch fire from the arc for the first time since the start of the Paris Games, connecting on six triples in the opening half.</p>
<p>But in the end, it was U.S. team&#8217;s night.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[Associated Press]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Paris Olympics]]></category>
<imageUrl></imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:33:44 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Serbia&#8217;s hot shooting not enough vs Steph Curry, Team USA</title>
		<link>https://sports.inquirer.net/579449/serbias-hot-shooting-not-enough-vs-steph-curry-team-usa</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:33:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sports.inquirer.net/579449/serbias-hot-shooting-not-enough-vs-steph-curry-team-usa</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>PARIS — Trailing and with its streak of four consecutive Olympic gold medals in danger, Team USA was trying desperately to mount a semifinal comeback.</p>
<p>There was only one problem — Serbia kept making 3-pointers.</p>
<p>And making them. And making them.</p>
<p>The Paris Olympics semifinal showdown between the four-time defending gold medal-winning Team USA and Serbia turned into a 3-point shooting contest.</p>
<p class="LC20lb MBeuO DKV0Md"><strong>READ: <a href="https://sports.inquirer.net/579393/paris-olympics-usa-beats-serbia-to-face-france-for-mens-basketball-gold">Team USA beats Serbia, faces France for men&#8217;s basketball gold</a></strong></p>
<p>Serbia nearly prevailed. And, in doing so, came within a late flurry of stunning the title favorites before losing 95-91, almost denying one of the most star-laden teams since the 1992 Dream Team a chance of another gold.</p>
<p>“I still believe that we could have won this game, a couple of possessions, a call goes our way, a couple of shots,&#8221; Serbia&#8217;s Bogdan Bogdanovic said. &#8220;But that is basketball. You should be proud even if you lose a game like this.”</p>
<p>Serbia made 15 of 39 shots from beyond the arc, compared with 16 of 32 by the Americans. It almost nullified nine 3-point makes by Stephen Curry — the NBA’s all-time leader in 3-point makes — who finished with 36 points.</p>
<p>It contributed to Serbia&#8217;s big leads during the game, which stretched to as much as 17 points.</p>
<p>“They came out and hit some amazingly tough shots in the first half,” Curry said. “You have to credit to them, they&#8217;re a really good team. &#8230; but to come back the way we did, like, I&#8217;ve seen a lot of Team USA basketball and that was a special one.”</p>
<p class="LC20lb MBeuO DKV0Md"><strong>READ: <a href="https://sports.inquirer.net/579414/durant-hails-god-like-steph-curry-after-heroics-for-team-usa">Durant hails &#8216;God-like&#8217; Steph Curry after heroics for Team USA</a></strong></p>
<div class="notranslate HGLrXd NJjxre iUh30 ojE3Fb">
<div class="q0vns">

</div>
</div>
<p>It left the Serbian players stunned as they shook hands after the game. Bogdanovic, who had 20 points including three 3-pointers, was in tears. At one point he pulled his jersey over his head and crouched to the ground as teammates consoled him.</p>
<p>Curry&#8217;s efforts left his teammates in awe of what they&#8217;ve seen so many nights on NBA floors, travel to the international level.</p>
<p>“Steph? Man, that was a godlike performance,&#8221; Kevin Durant said. &#8220;That was tough. It felt like he was struggling throughout the whole tournament. We always said: Each night it’ll be somebody different. Tonight, he showed up in a way that, man, God was with him tonight. He was with us tonight, through Steph.”</p>
<p class="LC20lb MBeuO DKV0Md">READ: <a href="https://sports.inquirer.net/578962/kevin-durant-becomes-team-usa-career-scoring-leader-in-olympics"><strong>Kevin Durant becomes Team USA scoring leader in Olympics</strong></a></p>
<p>The ultimate example of Serbia’s hot night from deep may have been late in the third quarter. The U.S. chopped what had been a 17-point deficit to 67-61.</p>
<p>Serbia responded with a 3 from Vasilije Micic. Then, after a pair of free throws by Marko Guduric and a miss by the U.S., Gurduric got free and drained another 3 and was fouled.</p>
<p>He hit the ensuing free throw to complete the four-point play.</p>
<p>The Serbians didn’t show any fear in the first half, shooting 54% from the field, including 10 of 19 from the 3-point line.</p>
<p>It canceled a half that saw Curry catch fire from the arc for the first time since the start of the Paris Games, connecting on six triples in the opening half.</p>
<p>But in the end, it was U.S. team&#8217;s night.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[Associated Press]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Paris Olympics]]></category>
<ArticleSlug><![CDATA[Basketball]]></ArticleSlug>
<ArticleSlug><![CDATA[Olympics]]></ArticleSlug>
<imageUrl>https://sports.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/AP24221758417031-scaled.jpg</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:33:44 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PNP says reported tunnels in Quiboloy compound an &#8216;open secret’</title>
		<link>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971229/pnp-says-reported-tunnels-in-quiboloy-compound-an-open-secret</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Eric Mendoza]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971229/pnp-says-reported-tunnels-in-quiboloy-compound-an-open-secret</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>MANILA, Philippines — The Philippine National Police (PNP) on Friday called the reported tunnels inside the Kingdom of Jesus Christ (KOJC) compound in Davao City an “open secret.”</p>
<p>PNP spokesperson Col. Jean Fajardo said this was one of the factors the police are considering when planning the serving of the warrant against embattled religious leader Pastor Apollo Quiboloy, who is believed to be<a href="https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1970786/quiboloy-staying-in-his-church-compound-davao-police-chief"> hiding in the sprawling 30-hectare compound.</a></p>
<p>“I think it’s an open secret,” Fajardo said of the reported tunnels in Quiboloy’s compound.</p>
<p>Last June 10, some 100 policemen stormed the premises of the KOJC compound to serve the warrants of arrest against Quiboloy, but they were prevented by its religious members from entering.</p>
<p>Fajardo recalled that there was “a deliberate attempt to derail and delay the service of warrant” against Quiboloy, noting that sirens were also heard in the compound during the June 10 incident.</p>
<p>“I don’t know if it’s a signal to anyone to give them the opportunity to hide and even escape,” Fajardo said of the sirens.</p>
<p>“This is one of the challenges we are facing with respect to the service of warrant against Pastor Quiboloy and other suspects,” she added.</p>
<p>Fajardo said the police have established checkpoints near the compound to prevent the suspects from leaving the area.</p>
<p>Authorities noted that there is a hangar for Quiboloy&#8217;s private aircraft at the KOJC, which he could use to escape, according to Davao police regional office director Brig. Gen. Nicolas Torre III.</p>
<p>One of Quiboloy&#8217;s helicopters was even recently active, but police then alerted the airport authorities, according to Torre.</p>
<p>The pilots of Quiboloy told the Civil Aviation Authority of the Philippines that they were only “warming up” the helicopter, according to Fajardo.</p>
<p>Fajardo also said authorities are closely monitoring the movement of Quiboloy’s air assets.</p>
<p>The police spokesperson also noted that one of Quiboloy’s private planes was covered by the freeze order of the Court of Appeals (CA).</p>
<p>CA on Thursday said it had <a href="https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971030/ca-orders-20-day-freeze-on-quiboloy-kojc-assets">imposed a 20-day freeze order on Quiboloy’s bank accounts, real estate properties, and other assets.</a></p>
<p>Furthermore, a P10 million reward would be given to anyone with information leading to the arrest of Quiboloy, according to Interior Secretary Benjamin Abalos Jr.</p>
<p><strong>READ: <a href="https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1927050/quiboloy-no-us-meddling-or-catch-me-if-you-can">Quiboloy: No US meddling—or catch me if you can</a></strong></p>
<p>Quiboloy and the five co-accused faced child abuse cases before the Davao City court. He also has standing arrest warrants for human trafficking issued by a Pasig City court.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[INQUIRER.net]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[PNP‎Quiboloy]]></category>
<imageUrl>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/files/2024/04/2024-April-29-Apollo-Quiboloy.jpg</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:19:24 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PNP says reported tunnels in Quiboloy compound an &#8216;open secret’</title>
		<link>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971229/pnp-says-reported-tunnels-in-quiboloy-compound-an-open-secret</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Eric Mendoza]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971229/pnp-says-reported-tunnels-in-quiboloy-compound-an-open-secret</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>MANILA, Philippines — The Philippine National Police (PNP) on Friday called the reported tunnels inside the Kingdom of Jesus Christ (KOJC) compound in Davao City an “open secret.”</p>
<p>PNP spokesperson Col. Jean Fajardo said this was one of the factors the police are considering when planning the serving of the warrant against embattled religious leader Pastor Apollo Quiboloy, who is believed to be<a href="https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1970786/quiboloy-staying-in-his-church-compound-davao-police-chief"> hiding in the sprawling 30-hectare compound.</a></p>
<p>“I think it’s an open secret,” Fajardo said of the reported tunnels in Quiboloy’s compound.</p>
<p>Last June 10, some 100 policemen stormed the premises of the KOJC compound to serve the warrants of arrest against Quiboloy, but they were prevented by its religious members from entering.</p>
<p>Fajardo recalled that there was “a deliberate attempt to derail and delay the service of warrant” against Quiboloy, noting that sirens were also heard in the compound during the June 10 incident.</p>
<p>“I don’t know if it’s a signal to anyone to give them the opportunity to hide and even escape,” Fajardo said of the sirens.</p>
<p>“This is one of the challenges we are facing with respect to the service of warrant against Pastor Quiboloy and other suspects,” she added.</p>
<p>Fajardo said the police have established checkpoints near the compound to prevent the suspects from leaving the area.</p>
<p>Authorities noted that there is a hangar for Quiboloy&#8217;s private aircraft at the KOJC, which he could use to escape, according to Davao police regional office director Brig. Gen. Nicolas Torre III.</p>
<p>One of Quiboloy&#8217;s helicopters was even recently active, but police then alerted the airport authorities, according to Torre.</p>
<p>The pilots of Quiboloy told the Civil Aviation Authority of the Philippines that they were only “warming up” the helicopter, according to Fajardo.</p>
<p>Fajardo also said authorities are closely monitoring the movement of Quiboloy’s air assets.</p>
<p>The police spokesperson also noted that one of Quiboloy’s private planes was covered by the freeze order of the Court of Appeals (CA).</p>
<p>CA on Thursday said it had <a href="https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971030/ca-orders-20-day-freeze-on-quiboloy-kojc-assets">imposed a 20-day freeze order on Quiboloy’s bank accounts, real estate properties, and other assets.</a></p>
<p>Furthermore, a P10 million reward would be given to anyone with information leading to the arrest of Quiboloy, according to Interior Secretary Benjamin Abalos Jr.</p>
<p><strong>READ: <a href="https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1927050/quiboloy-no-us-meddling-or-catch-me-if-you-can">Quiboloy: No US meddling—or catch me if you can</a></strong></p>
<p>Quiboloy and the five co-accused faced child abuse cases before the Davao City court. He also has standing arrest warrants for human trafficking issued by a Pasig City court.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[INQUIRER.net]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[PNP‎]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[ Quiboloy]]></category>
<section><![CDATA[Nation]]></section>
<imageUrl>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/files/2024/04/2024-April-29-Apollo-Quiboloy.jpg</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:19:24 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Michele Gumabao, Aldo Panlilio now engaged</title>
		<link>https://entertainment.inquirer.net/570572/michele-gumabao-aldo-panlilio-now-engaged</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jessica Ann Evangelista]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://entertainment.inquirer.net/570572/michele-gumabao-aldo-panlilio-now-engaged</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Celebrity athlete and beauty queen <a href="https://entertainment.inquirer.net/560309/michele-gumabao-arci-munoz-richard-armstrong-share-pride-month-message" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Michele Gumabao</a> is now engaged to PBA strength and conditioning coach Aldo Panlilio.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The couple announced their engagement on Instagram by sharing sweet photos of them that show off Gumabao&#8217;s engagement ring.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;8/8 celebrating our 8th year, and it’s <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/267e.png" alt="♾" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (infinity) with you [ring emoji],&#8221; wrote Panlilio in his caption. Gumabao, on the other hand, captioned her post with the same reference, &#8220;8 to <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/267e.png" alt="♾" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (infinity) with you.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In its <a href="https://www.facebook.com/niceprintphotographyexigeweddings/posts/pfbid0vKUJpUSbHiFq9fY9P1zs1wdJkiXYS44X87sYBrCF9e7MgPPmX4YheYxHWQm6B219l" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Facebook post,</a> Nice Print Photography, which was hired to take the couple&#8217;s official photos, shared that the wedding proposal took place in Tokyo, Japan.</span></p>
<blockquote class="instagram-media" style="background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-aVq_KzN3o/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14">
<div style="padding: 16px;">
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;"></div>
<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style="color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;">View this post on Instagram</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style="width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;"><a style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-aVq_KzN3o/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A post shared by Aldo <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f17f.png" alt="🅿" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />anlilio (@aldopanlilio12)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<p><script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Celebrity friends and fans took to the comments section to extend their congratulations to the couple.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“FINALLY!!! [heart eyes emoji] CONGRATS GUYS!!! [red heart emoji],” former PBB housemate and beauty queen Samantha Bernardo commented.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kapuso actress Nadine Samonte also wrote, “Yay finally [heart eyes, red heart emojis} congrats again, Chelle and Aldo [heart sign emoji].”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gumabao&#8217;s brother and sister, Marco and Marielle, also reacted to their sibling&#8217;s engagement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I CAN FINALLY POST TOO [laughing emoji]. I love you guys!!!! [crying, blue heart emojis],&#8221; wrote Marielle.</span></p>
<blockquote class="instagram-media" style="background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-aID41SaaR/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14">
<div style="padding: 16px;">
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;"></div>
<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style="color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;">View this post on Instagram</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style="width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;"><a style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-aID41SaaR/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A post shared by MG (@gumabaomichele)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<p><script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gumabao and Panlilio met in a restaurant over an arranged date by one of their friends.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;A friend set us up at his restaurant, Sobremesa in Pasig City. I just tagged along and got invites. I already knew of her, so I gave it a chance. As for why Michele gave it a chance? Maybe because (the restaurant) was near her game,&#8221; the PBA coach recalled in an interview.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;What he said! Sabi ko sa kanya punta na lang siya! After that, we just kept talking. We talked every day — as in, every day until today!&#8221; added Gumabao. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The volleyball player described her now-fiancé as &#8220;smart and entertaining.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, aside from being an athlete, Gumabao is also a beauty pageant titleholder. She was crowned Binibining Pilipinas Globe in 2018. She also finished as the second runner-up during the first edition of Miss Universe Philippines.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Right now, she is signed with the Creamline Cool Smashers of the Premier Volleyball League (PVL).</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[INQUIRER.net]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Michele Gumabao]]></category>
<ArticleSlug><![CDATA[Celebrities and Showbiz]]></ArticleSlug>
<imageUrl>https://entertainment.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-09-at-12.05.40 PM.png</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:20:19 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Michele Gumabao, Aldo Panlilio now engaged</title>
		<link>https://entertainment.inquirer.net/570572/michele-gumabao-aldo-panlilio-now-engaged</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jessica Ann Evangelista]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://entertainment.inquirer.net/570572/michele-gumabao-aldo-panlilio-now-engaged</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Celebrity athlete and beauty queen <a href="https://entertainment.inquirer.net/560309/michele-gumabao-arci-munoz-richard-armstrong-share-pride-month-message" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Michele Gumabao</a> is now engaged to PBA strength and conditioning coach Aldo Panlilio.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The couple announced their engagement on Instagram by sharing sweet photos of them that show off Gumabao&#8217;s engagement ring.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;8/8 celebrating our 8th year, and it’s <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/267e.png" alt="♾" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (infinity) with you [ring emoji],&#8221; wrote Panlilio in his caption. Gumabao, on the other hand, captioned her post with the same reference, &#8220;8 to <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/267e.png" alt="♾" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (infinity) with you.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In its <a href="https://www.facebook.com/niceprintphotographyexigeweddings/posts/pfbid0vKUJpUSbHiFq9fY9P1zs1wdJkiXYS44X87sYBrCF9e7MgPPmX4YheYxHWQm6B219l" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Facebook post,</a> Nice Print Photography, which was hired to take the couple&#8217;s official photos, shared that the wedding proposal took place in Tokyo, Japan.</span></p>
<blockquote class="instagram-media" style="background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-aVq_KzN3o/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14">
<div style="padding: 16px;">
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;"></div>
<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style="color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;">View this post on Instagram</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style="width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;"><a style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-aVq_KzN3o/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A post shared by Aldo <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f17f.png" alt="🅿" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />anlilio (@aldopanlilio12)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<p><script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Celebrity friends and fans took to the comments section to extend their congratulations to the couple.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“FINALLY!!! [heart eyes emoji] CONGRATS GUYS!!! [red heart emoji],” former PBB housemate and beauty queen Samantha Bernardo commented.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kapuso actress Nadine Samonte also wrote, “Yay finally [heart eyes, red heart emojis} congrats again, Chelle and Aldo [heart sign emoji].”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gumabao&#8217;s brother and sister, Marco and Marielle, also reacted to their sibling&#8217;s engagement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I CAN FINALLY POST TOO [laughing emoji]. I love you guys!!!! [crying, blue heart emojis],&#8221; wrote Marielle.</span></p>
<blockquote class="instagram-media" style="background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-aID41SaaR/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14">
<div style="padding: 16px;">
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;"></div>
<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style="color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;">View this post on Instagram</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style="width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;"><a style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-aID41SaaR/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A post shared by MG (@gumabaomichele)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<p><script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gumabao and Panlilio met in a restaurant over an arranged date by one of their friends.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;A friend set us up at his restaurant, Sobremesa in Pasig City. I just tagged along and got invites. I already knew of her, so I gave it a chance. As for why Michele gave it a chance? Maybe because (the restaurant) was near her game,&#8221; the PBA coach recalled in an interview.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;What he said! Sabi ko sa kanya punta na lang siya! After that, we just kept talking. We talked every day — as in, every day until today!&#8221; added the Gumabao. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The volleyball player described her now-fiancé as &#8220;smart and entertaining.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, aside from being an athlete, Gumabao is also a beauty pageant titleholder. She was crowned Binibining Pilipinas Globe in 2018. She also finished as the second runner-up during the first edition of Miss Universe Philippines.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Right now, she is signed with the Creamline Cool Smashers of the Premier Volleyball League (PVL).</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[INQUIRER.net]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Michele Gumabao]]></category>
<ArticleSlug><![CDATA[Celebrities and Showbiz]]></ArticleSlug>
<imageUrl>https://entertainment.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-09-at-12.05.40 PM.png</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:17:59 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Transport groups call for increase in vehicular liability insurance</title>
		<link>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971226/transport-groups-call-for-increase-in-vehicular-liability-insurance</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dianne Sampang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971226/transport-groups-call-for-increase-in-vehicular-liability-insurance</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>MANILA, Philippines — Various groups on Friday called on the Insurance Commission (IC) and Land Transportation Office (LTO) to increase the insurance for vehicular accidents to ensure the safety and well-being of motorists and victims.</p>
<p>In a press conference, Pasang Masda National President Roberto Martin said that the Magnificent 7 and other transport groups wrote a formal letter dated Thursday, August 8 to Commissioner Atty. Reynaldo Regalado of IC and LTO Chief Atty. Vigor Mendoza.</p>
<p>Magnificent 7 is composed of Pasang Masda, Liga ng Transportasyon at Operators sa Pilipinas (LTOP), Alliance of Transport Operators and Drivers Association of the Philippines (ALTODAP), Alliance of Concerned Transport Organizations (ACTO), Federation of Jeepney Operators and Drivers Association of the Philippines (FEJODAP), Stop and Go Coalition, and UV-Express Federation of the Philippines.</p>
<p>“Alam natin, halos araw-araw may naaaksidente. Kaya po kami, nag-iisip ang grupo ng magandang benepisyo doon sa mabibiktima ng public transport driver, private car owners, at para po sa kapakanan ng kanilang pamilya,” said Martin.</p>
<p>(We all know that people get into accidents every day. That’s why the group thought of the benefits for the victims of public transport drivers and private car owners. This is also for the welfare of their families.)</p>
<p><strong>READ: </strong><a href="https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1941842/doh-12000-killed-on-roads-each-year"><strong>DOH: 12,000 killed on roads each year</strong></a></p>
<p>“Wala po kaming interes doon kung hindi ‘yong mga maiiwan [na] makatanggap ng kung hindi man sapat, tama lang po para doon sa maiiwan ng mga naaksidente,” he added.</p>
<p>(We don’t have any other interest except for ensuring that those left behind receive not necessarily a lot, but enough for those who have lost someone in an accident.)</p>
<p>The groups called for an increase in the death indemnity for compulsory monitor vehicle liability insurance from P200,000 to P400,000, and permanent disability indemnity from P50,000 to P100,000. The groups also wanted the all-risk insurance to have property loss indemnity worth P100,000.</p>
<p>In a radio interview last May, Department of Health Assistant Secretary Albert Domingo said that an average of 12,000 Filipinos are killed every year due to road accidents. Domingo also said that road accidents in the country increased by 39 percent from 2011 to 2021.</p>
<p>“Road traffic deaths in 2011 were 7,938. This went up to 11,096 in 2021. Of these deaths, 84 percent were males. Road accidents are a major cause of deaths of children in the Philippines,” he added.</p>
<p>President Ferdinand Marcos Jr. refused to accept the Senate&#8217;s proposal to reject the implementation of the public utility vehicle modernization program (PUVMP), saying that more than 80 percent of jeepney operators and drivers already consolidated their transport units.</p>
<p>“Well, I disagree with them (senators). They are saying that this was rushed. The [program] has been postponed seven times. Those who have been objecting and asking for [its] suspension are in the minority. Eighty percent have already consolidated,” said Marcos in an interview on Wednesday.</p>
<p><strong>READ: </strong><a href="https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1970616/puv-modernization-still-a-go-says-president"><strong>PUV modernization still a go, says President</strong></a></p>
<p>The Magnificent 7, a pro-PUVMP, expressed their gratitude to the President for his stance on the program, saying that they hope that this will ease the doubts of the operators and drivers.</p>
<p>“Sa lahat ng sumusuporta sa ating modernisasyon, sa transportasyon, eh mawalan na ng agam-agam ang bawat isa, lalo na ang maliit na operator na talaga pong pumasok sa loob ng konsolidasyon kahit sa iba’t ibang mga kooperatiba,” said Jephraim Gochangco, National President of FEJODAP.</p>
<p>(To all who support modernization in transportation, set aside any doubts and fully join the consolidation, especially the small operators, even if it&#8217;s through different cooperatives.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[INQUIRER.net]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[InsuranceTransportvehicular accident]]></category>
<imageUrl>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/viber_image_2024-08-09_13-03-35-552.jpg</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:04:09 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Transport groups call for increase in vehicular liability insurance</title>
		<link>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971226/transport-groups-call-for-increase-in-vehicular-liability-insurance</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dianne Sampang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971226/transport-groups-call-for-increase-in-vehicular-liability-insurance</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>MANILA, Philippines — Various groups on Friday called on the Insurance Commission (IC) and Land Transportation Office (LTO) to increase the insurance for vehicular accidents to ensure the safety and well-being of motorists and victims.</p>
<p>In a press conference, Pasang Masda National President Roberto Martin said that the Magnificent 7 and other transport groups wrote a formal letter dated Thursday, August 8 to Commissioner Atty. Reynaldo Regalado of IC and LTO Chief Atty. Vigor Mendoza.</p>
<p>Magnificent 7 is composed of Pasang Masda, Liga ng Transportasyon at Operators sa Pilipinas (LTOP), Alliance of Transport Operators and Drivers Association of the Philippines (ALTODAP), Alliance of Concerned Transport Organizations (ACTO), Federation of Jeepney Operators and Drivers Association of the Philippines (FEJODAP), Stop and Go Coalition, and UV-Express Federation of the Philippines.</p>
<p>“Alam natin, halos araw-araw may naaaksidente. Kaya po kami, nag-iisip ang grupo ng magandang benepisyo doon sa mabibiktima ng public transport driver, private car owners, at para po sa kapakanan ng kanilang pamilya,” said Martin.</p>
<p>(We all know that people get into accidents every day. That’s why the group thought of the benefits for the victims of public transport drivers and private car owners. This is also for the welfare of their families.)</p>
<p><strong>READ: </strong><a href="https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1941842/doh-12000-killed-on-roads-each-year"><strong>DOH: 12,000 killed on roads each year</strong></a></p>
<p>“Wala po kaming interes doon kung hindi ‘yong mga maiiwan [na] makatanggap ng kung hindi man sapat, tama lang po para doon sa maiiwan ng mga naaksidente,” he added.</p>
<p>(We don’t have any other interest except for ensuring that those left behind receive not necessarily a lot, but enough for those who have lost someone in an accident.)</p>
<p>The groups called for an increase in the death indemnity for compulsory monitor vehicle liability insurance from P200,000 to P400,000, and permanent disability indemnity from P50,000 to P100,000. The groups also wanted the all-risk insurance to have property loss indemnity worth P100,000.</p>
<p>In a radio interview last May, Department of Health Assistant Secretary Albert Domingo said that an average of 12,000 Filipinos are killed every year due to road accidents. Domingo also said that road accidents in the country increased by 39 percent from 2011 to 2021.</p>
<p>“Road traffic deaths in 2011 were 7,938. This went up to 11,096 in 2021. Of these deaths, 84 percent were males. Road accidents are a major cause of deaths of children in the Philippines,” he added.</p>
<p>President Ferdinand Marcos Jr. refused to accept the Senate&#8217;s proposal to reject the implementation of the public utility vehicle modernization program (PUVMP), saying that more than 80 percent of jeepney operators and drivers already consolidated their transport units.</p>
<p>“Well, I disagree with them (senators). They are saying that this was rushed. The [program] has been postponed seven times. Those who have been objecting and asking for [its] suspension are in the minority. Eighty percent have already consolidated,” said Marcos in an interview on Wednesday.</p>
<p><strong>READ: </strong><a href="https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1970616/puv-modernization-still-a-go-says-president"><strong>PUV modernization still a go, says President</strong></a></p>
<p>The Magnificent 7, a pro-PUVMP, expressed their gratitude to the President for his stance on the program, saying that they hope that this will ease the doubts of the operators and drivers.</p>
<p>“Sa lahat ng sumusuporta sa ating modernisasyon, sa transportasyon, eh mawalan na ng agam-agam ang bawat isa, lalo na ang maliit na operator na talaga pong pumasok sa loob ng konsolidasyon kahit sa iba’t ibang mga kooperatiba,” said Jephraim Gochangco, National President of FEJODAP.</p>
<p>(To all who support modernization in transportation, set aside any doubts and fully join the consolidation, especially the small operators, even if it&#8217;s through different cooperatives.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[INQUIRER.net]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Insurance]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[ Transport]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[ vehicular accident]]></category>
<section><![CDATA[Nation]]></section>
<imageUrl>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/viber_image_2024-08-09_13-03-35-552.jpg</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:04:09 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Samsung recalls 1M electric ranges after numerous fire, injury reports</title>
		<link>https://business.inquirer.net/473936/samsung-recalls-1m-electric-ranges-after-numerous-fire-injury-reports</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://business.inquirer.net/473936/samsung-recalls-1m-electric-ranges-after-numerous-fire-injury-reports</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>NEW YORK — Samsung is recalling more than 1.12 million electric ranges used for stovetops after reports of 250 fires and dozens of injuries.</p>
<p>According to a Thursday notice from the U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, these slide-in ranges have front-mounted knobs that can be activated by accident if humans or pets unintentionally contact or bump into them. That poses a fire hazard.</p>
<p>To date, Samsung has received more than 300 reports of the knobs activating unintentionally since 2013, the CPSC noted, and the now-recalled ranges have been involved in about 250 fires. At least 18 of those fires caused extensive property damage and seven involved pet deaths, according to the Commission.</p>
<p class="entry-title"><strong>READ: <a href="https://business.inquirer.net/467279/samsung-electronics-forecasts-major-q2-profit-jump">Samsung Electronics forecasts major Q2 profit jump</a></strong></p>
<p>In addition, the CPSC added, about 40 injuries have been reported, including eight that required medical attention.</p>
<p>Consumers can identify whether their slide-in electric range is included in this recall by looking at the model number printed on the product. Both Samsung and the CPSC have published a list of affected models online.</p>
<p>The recalled ranges were sold between May 2013 and August 2024 online at Samsung.com as well as in retailers nationwide — including Best Buy, Costco, Home Depot and Lowe&#8217;s.</p>
<p>Consumers in possession of a recalled range are urged to contact New Jersey-based Samsung Electronics America for a free set of knob locks or covers compatible for installation with their model. In the meantime, those impacted should take extra caution to keep children and pets away from the knobs, and check their range before leaving the house or going to bed to make sure it&#8217;s off, the CPSC said.</p>
<p>As part of general stovetop and oven safety, the Commission added that consumers should “never place, leave, or store anything on the top of your range” when not in use — as such items can ignite if it&#8217;s accidentally activated.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[Associated Press]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[electronicssamsung]]></category>
<imageUrl>https://business.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/AP24221551296177-scaled.jpg</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:57:09 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Samsung recalls 1M electric ranges after numerous fire, injury reports</title>
		<link>https://business.inquirer.net/473936/samsung-recalls-1m-electric-ranges-after-numerous-fire-injury-reports</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://business.inquirer.net/473936/samsung-recalls-1m-electric-ranges-after-numerous-fire-injury-reports</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>NEW YORK — Samsung is recalling more than 1.12 million electric ranges used for stovetops after reports of 250 fires and dozens of injuries.</p>
<p>According to a Thursday notice from the U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, these slide-in ranges have front-mounted knobs that can be activated by accident if humans or pets unintentionally contact or bump into them. That poses a fire hazard.</p>
<p>To date, Samsung has received more than 300 reports of the knobs activating unintentionally since 2013, the CPSC noted, and the now-recalled ranges have been involved in about 250 fires. At least 18 of those fires caused extensive property damage and seven involved pet deaths, according to the Commission.</p>
<p class="entry-title"><strong>READ: <a href="https://business.inquirer.net/467279/samsung-electronics-forecasts-major-q2-profit-jump">Samsung Electronics forecasts major Q2 profit jump</a></strong></p>
<p>In addition, the CPSC added, about 40 injuries have been reported, including eight that required medical attention.</p>
<p>Consumers can identify whether their slide-in electric range is included in this recall by looking at the model number printed on the product. Both Samsung and the CPSC have published a list of affected models online.</p>
<p>The recalled ranges were sold between May 2013 and August 2024 online at Samsung.com as well as in retailers nationwide — including Best Buy, Costco, Home Depot and Lowe&#8217;s.</p>
<p>Consumers in possession of a recalled range are urged to contact New Jersey-based Samsung Electronics America for a free set of knob locks or covers compatible for installation with their model. In the meantime, those impacted should take extra caution to keep children and pets away from the knobs, and check their range before leaving the house or going to bed to make sure it&#8217;s off, the CPSC said.</p>
<p>As part of general stovetop and oven safety, the Commission added that consumers should “never place, leave, or store anything on the top of your range” when not in use — as such items can ignite if it&#8217;s accidentally activated.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
<imageUrl>https://business.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/AP24221551296177-scaled.jpg</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:57:09 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bb. Pilipinas 2024 runners-up will also undergo international pageant preps</title>
		<link>https://entertainment.inquirer.net/570559/bb-pilipinas-2024-runners-up-will-also-undergo-international-pageant-preps</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Armin P. Adina]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://entertainment.inquirer.net/570559/bb-pilipinas-2024-runners-up-will-also-undergo-international-pageant-preps</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-weight: 400;">A month has passed since <strong><a href="https://entertainment.inquirer.net/565284/binibining-pilipinas-behind-the-scenes-and-other-highlights" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Binibining Pilipinas International Myrna Esguerra</a></strong> and Binibining Pilipinas Globe Jasmin Bungay received their respective<strong><a href="https://entertainment.inquirer.net/570195/binibining-pilipinas-2024-queens-get-second-go-at-pageant-qas" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> national titles</a></strong> and earned the responsibility to represent the Philippines on the global arena. But it will not be just the two of them who will buckle down to training, because their runners-up Christal Jean Dela Cruz and Trisha Martinez are also tasked to undergo the same preparation regimen as them.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As first and second runners-up, respectively, Dela Cruz and Martinez are not just mere “ladies-in-waiting” in the event that the original representative would become unable to compete abroad; the Binibining Pilipinas Charities Inc. (BPCI) may also tap any one of them should the organization acquire a new franchise that would require another delegate to be sent right away.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“It&#8217;s really a critical role. Not that I wish anything [will] happen to my queens. No, that&#8217;s the last thing that I want. But being a runner-up is really a big shoe to fill. We really have to prepare as if we are competing also internationally,” Martinez told INQUIRER.net in an interview.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">She said she is focused on fulfilling her duties and responsibilities as a runner-up. And Dela Cruz echoed the same declaration, saying, “Yes, as runners-up, that&#8217;s what [BPCI] said to us. And that&#8217;s what we are prepared to do as well.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The two, along with Esguerra and Bungay, emerged on top of the field of 40 aspirants who competed in the 60th anniversary edition of the longest-running national beauty pageant in the Philippines, an epic celebration that saw more than 100 former winners gathered together on stage. The celebration took place at the Smart Araneta Coliseum at the Araneta City in Quezon City on July 7.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“The experience is extraordinary. I can really feel that this batch was really special. I joined last year and it&#8217;s totally different. I can really feel that BPCI pulled out all the stops,” said Martinez, who shared that the moment will be something worth telling her future children.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Dela Cruz, for her part, shared getting goosebumps upon learning about the massive reunion of Bb. Pilipinas alumnae. “We were all cheering, and so I&#8217;m happy about that. Because aside from being a candidate, imagine standing with those amazing women who have fulfilled their duties and responsibility into being a queen with a purpose. Such a remarkable moment for me, and I will forever cherish that moment,” she said.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The two ladies also shared who among the previous runners-up were their favorites. For Martinez, it is Gabrielle Basiano from 2021, and it was Pia Wurtzbach from 2013 for Dela Cruz. Both eventually became Binibining Pilipinas titleholders in succeeding participations.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“I&#8217;m very close to Gabby [Basiano, 2022 Bb. Pilipinas Intercontinental], and actually she&#8217;s one of the queens [who] told me ‘if ever you will be joining again, you will be facing a lot of criticisms, you will receive a lot of bashing. But it&#8217;s gonna be worth it, you just have to be there, you just have to show up.’ So I really owe Gabby for that advice,” Martinez said.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Dela Cruz, meanwhile, cited Wurtzbach’s perseverance before finally becoming Miss Universe in 2015. “She joined three times, and one of those she ended up being first runner-up. And she&#8217;s one of the judges during the coronation night. She really gave me an inspiration, that your journey doesn&#8217;t really stop here. You still have a long way to go and you just have to pursue what you want, and what you truly love [and] desire,” she said.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">They will be as busy as the titleholders, but with a lower prize package and an anxiety-enducing period of uncertainty whether they will indeed join an international competition or not. But Martinez said she is grateful, nonetheless.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“I’m really very happy. Just to have this sash, it’s a different feeling. It’s always the goal, you always aim for the highest. I have this perspective in life, even [when] I took the board exam, my goal is to be a topnotcher, so that if ever I will not be able to reach the top, I&#8217;m still there. So it&#8217;s the same mindset that I have here in Bb. I aimed for the top, I&#8217;m still here. So, I&#8217;m really happy about it, I&#8217;m really grateful for this that I never thought about being so close to a title. And I think it&#8217;s really destiny,” she said.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As for Dela Cruz, she has already declared that a second trip back on the Binibini stage is highly likely. “I&#8217;m so grateful that I get to be part of the legacy and I can forever say that ‘once a Binibini, always a Binibini,’ right? But I&#8217;m still young and I&#8217;m not closing any doors yet,” she said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[INQUIRER.net]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Binibining Pilipinas]]></category>
<ArticleSlug><![CDATA[Beauty Pageants]]></ArticleSlug>
<imageUrl>https://entertainment.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/7A65FA0F-52E0-40FE-9FCA-183AE0D9EE16.jpeg</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:57:23 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bb. Pilipinas 2024 runners-up will also undergo international pageant preps</title>
		<link>https://entertainment.inquirer.net/570559/bb-pilipinas-2024-runners-up-will-also-undergo-international-pageant-preps</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Armin P. Adina]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://entertainment.inquirer.net/570559/bb-pilipinas-2024-runners-up-will-also-undergo-international-pageant-preps</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-weight: 400;">A month has passed since <strong><a href="https://entertainment.inquirer.net/565284/binibining-pilipinas-behind-the-scenes-and-other-highlights" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Binibining Pilipinas International Myrna Esguerra</a></strong> and Binibining Pilipinas Globe Jasmin Bungay received their respective<strong><a href="https://entertainment.inquirer.net/570195/binibining-pilipinas-2024-queens-get-second-go-at-pageant-qas" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> national titles</a></strong> and earned the responsibility to represent the Philippines on the global arena. But it will not be just the two of them who will buckle down to training, because their runners-up Christal Jean Dela Cruz and Trisha Martinez are also tasked to undergo the same preparation regimen as them.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As first and second runners-up, respectively, Dela Cruz and Martinez are not just mere “ladies-in-waiting” in the event that the original representative would become unable to compete abroad; the Binibining Pilipinas Charities Inc. (BPCI) may also tap any one of them should the organization acquire a new franchise that would require another delegate to be sent right away.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“It&#8217;s really a critical role. Not that I wish anything [will] happen to my queens. No, that&#8217;s the last thing that I want. But being a runner-up is really a big shoe to fill. We really have to prepare as if we are competing also internationally,” Martinez told INQUIRER.net in an interview.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">She said she is focused on fulfilling her duties and responsibilities as a runner-up. And Dela Cruz echoed the same declaration, saying, “Yes, as runners-up, that&#8217;s what [BPCI] said to us. And that&#8217;s what we are prepared to do as well.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The two, along with Esguerra and Bungay, emerged on top of the field of 40 aspirants who competed in the 60th anniversary edition of the longest-running national beauty pageant in the Philippines, an epic celebration that saw more than 100 former winners gathered together on stage. The celebration took place at the Smart Araneta Coliseum at the Araneta City in Quezon City on July 7.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“The experience is extraordinary. I can really feel that this batch was really special. I joined last year and it&#8217;s totally different. I can really feel that BPCI pulled out all the stops,” said Martinez, who shared that the moment will be something worth telling her future children.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Dela Cruz, for her part, shared getting goosebumps upon learning about the massive reunion of Bb. Pilipinas alumnae. “We were all cheering, and so I&#8217;m happy about that. Because aside from being a candidate, imagine standing with those amazing women who have fulfilled their duties and responsibility into being a queen with a purpose. Such a remarkable moment for me, and I will forever cherish that moment,” she said.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The two ladies also shared who among the previous runners-up were their favorites. For Martinez, it is Gabrielle Basiano from 2021, and it was Pia Wurtzbach from 2013 for Dela Cruz. Both eventually became Binibining Pilipinas titleholders in succeeding participations.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“I&#8217;m very close to Gabby [Basiano, 2022 Bb. Pilipinas Intercontinental], and actually she&#8217;s one of the queens [who] told me ‘if ever you will be joining again, you will be facing a lot of criticisms, you will receive a lot of bashing. But it&#8217;s gonna be worth it, you just have to be there, you just have to show up.’ So I really owe Gabby for that advice,” Martinez said.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Dela Cruz, meanwhile, cited Wurtzbach’s perseverance before finally becoming Miss Universe in 2015. “She joined three times, and one of those she ended up being first runner-up. And she&#8217;s one of the judges during the coronation night. She really gave me an inspiration, that your journey doesn&#8217;t really stop here. You still have a long way to go and you just have to pursue what you want, and what you truly love [and] desire,” she said.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">They will be as busy as the titleholders, but with a lower prize package and an anxiety-enducing period of uncertainty whether they will indeed join an international competition or not. But Martinez said she is grateful, nonetheless.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“I’m really very happy. Just to have this sash, it’s a different feeling. It’s always the goal, you always aim for the highest. I have this perspective in life, even [when] I took the board exam, my goal is to be a topnotcher, so that if ever I will not be able to reach the top, I&#8217;m still there. So it&#8217;s the same mindset that I have here in Bb. I aimed for the top, I&#8217;m still here. So, I&#8217;m really happy about it, I&#8217;m really grateful for this that I never thought about being so close to a title. And I think it&#8217;s really destiny,” she said.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As for Dela Cruz, she has already declared that a second trip back on the Binibini stage is highly likely. “I&#8217;m so grateful that I get to be part of the legacy and I can forever say that ‘once a Binibini, always a Binibini,’ right? But I&#8217;m still young and I&#8217;m not closing any doors yet,” she said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[INQUIRER.net]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Binibining Pilipinas]]></category>
<ArticleSlug><![CDATA[Beauty Pageants]]></ArticleSlug>
<imageUrl>https://entertainment.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/7A65FA0F-52E0-40FE-9FCA-183AE0D9EE16.jpeg</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:55:24 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Probe underway as Subic hotel apologizes for alleged food poisoning</title>
		<link>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971218/probe-underway-as-subic-hotel-apologizes-for-alleged-food-poisoning</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonna Rose Aglibot]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971218/probe-underway-as-subic-hotel-apologizes-for-alleged-food-poisoning</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>SUBIC BAY FREEPORT — A hotel inside this free port has issued a public apology after a suspected food poisoning affected village officials from San Carlos City in Pangasinan.</p>
<p>In a statement on Thursday, Aug. 8, Jorgen Michael Te,  director of sales and marketing at Subic Bay Travellers Hotel (SBTH), announced that the hotel management was investigating the cause of the alleged food poisoning in coordination with the Subic Bay Metropolitan Authority (SBMA), the Olongapo City government and other agencies,</p>
<p>Te confirmed that food samples from the breakfast and lunch meals were sent to the Department of Health Region 3 for analysis.</p>
<p>He said water filters, samples of filtered water, and ice cubes from the hotel’s ice maker were submitted to Subicwater for testing.</p>
<p>&#8220;The hotel management commits to defray medical and hospitalization costs and whatever needs may be necessary to alleviate the concerns of those affected,&#8221; said Te.</p>
<p>While awaiting the test results, Te assured the public that the hotel would implement measures to ensure the safety of all stakeholders in every aspect of its operations.</p>
<p>&#8220;The overall comfort and well-being of hotel guests remains the primary mission of the hotel, and we commit to stringently undertake corrective actions to ensure premium quality service for our guests,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>SBTH also thanked San Carlos City Mayor Julier Resuello, the SBMA, the Olongapo City government, and the Philippine Red Cross for their prompt emergency response.</p>
<p>Armie Llamas, deputy administrator for corporate communication at the SBMA, said the laboratory results from the food samples were expected within four to five days. Water filter test results are anticipated within 24 to 48 hours.</p>
<p>Despite the ongoing investigation, the hotel’s restaurant remains operational. The Public Health and Safety Department (PHSD) has issued a show-cause order to the establishment.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, 163 village officials, primarily Sangguniang Kabataan (SK) officials from Pangasinan, exhibited symptoms of food poisoning after consuming lunch at the hotel during a seminar.</p>
<p>The affected individuals were taken to hospitals within the freeport and nearby Olongapo City, but have since been discharged and returned to Pangasinan.</p>
<p>In a phone interview, Mark Jerico Calma, an SK councilor from Barangay Ano in San Carlos City, noted that two of his five colleagues who attended the Gender Awareness and Sensitivity seminar experienced symptoms of food poisoning.</p>
<p>According to Calma, the chop suey served during lunch had a sour taste, raising concerns about its freshness.</p>
<p>The first batch of the three-day Gender Awareness and Development seminar, which began on Aug. 5, was organized by the San Carlos City local government and attended by more than 300 SK officials, including the mayor, vice mayor, and city council members.</p>
<p>Due to the incident, the San Carlos City LGU has canceled the second batch of the seminar, which was scheduled for Aug. 7–9 at the same hotel. INQ</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[Inquirer Central Luzon]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[food poisoningSubic]]></category>
<imageUrl>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/Subic-Zambales-food-poisoning.png</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:44:08 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Probe underway as Subic hotel apologizes for alleged food poisoning</title>
		<link>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971218/probe-underway-as-subic-hotel-apologizes-for-alleged-food-poisoning</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonna Rose Aglibot]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1971218/probe-underway-as-subic-hotel-apologizes-for-alleged-food-poisoning</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>SUBIC BAY FREEPORT — A hotel inside this free port has issued a public apology after a suspected food poisoning affected village officials from San Carlos City in Pangasinan.</p>
<p>In a statement on Thursday, Aug. 8, Jorgen Michael Te,  director of sales and marketing at Subic Bay Travellers Hotel (SBTH), announced that the hotel management was investigating the cause of the alleged food poisoning in coordination with the Subic Bay Metropolitan Authority (SBMA), the Olongapo City government and other agencies,</p>
<p>Te confirmed that food samples from the breakfast and lunch meals were sent to the Department of Health Region 3 for analysis.</p>
<p>He said water filters, samples of filtered water, and ice cubes from the hotel’s ice maker were submitted to Subicwater for testing.</p>
<p>&#8220;The hotel management commits to defray medical and hospitalization costs and whatever needs may be necessary to alleviate the concerns of those affected,&#8221; said Te.</p>
<p>While awaiting the test results, Te assured the public that the hotel would implement measures to ensure the safety of all stakeholders in every aspect of its operations.</p>
<p>&#8220;The overall comfort and well-being of hotel guests remains the primary mission of the hotel, and we commit to stringently undertake corrective actions to ensure premium quality service for our guests,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>SBTH also thanked San Carlos City Mayor Julier Resuello, the SBMA, the Olongapo City government, and the Philippine Red Cross for their prompt emergency response.</p>
<p>Armie Llamas, deputy administrator for corporate communication at the SBMA, said the laboratory results from the food samples were expected within four to five days. Water filter test results are anticipated within 24 to 48 hours.</p>
<p>Despite the ongoing investigation, the hotel’s restaurant remains operational. The Public Health and Safety Department (PHSD) has issued a show-cause order to the establishment.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, 163 village officials, primarily Sangguniang Kabataan (SK) officials from Pangasinan, exhibited symptoms of food poisoning after consuming lunch at the hotel during a seminar.</p>
<p>The affected individuals were taken to hospitals within the freeport and nearby Olongapo City, but have since been discharged and returned to Pangasinan.</p>
<p>In a phone interview, Mark Jerico Calma, an SK councilor from Barangay Ano in San Carlos City, noted that two of his five colleagues who attended the Gender Awareness and Sensitivity seminar experienced symptoms of food poisoning.</p>
<p>According to Calma, the chop suey served during lunch had a sour taste, raising concerns about its freshness.</p>
<p>The first batch of the three-day Gender Awareness and Development seminar, which began on Aug. 5, was organized by the San Carlos City local government and attended by more than 300 SK officials, including the mayor, vice mayor, and city council members.</p>
<p>Due to the incident, the San Carlos City LGU has canceled the second batch of the seminar, which was scheduled for Aug. 7–9 at the same hotel. INQ</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[Inquirer Central Luzon]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[food poisoning]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[ Subic]]></category>
<section><![CDATA[Regions]]></section>
<imageUrl>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/Subic-Zambales-food-poisoning.png</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:44:08 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>E-commerce tycoon Huang tops China&#8217;s rich list</title>
		<link>https://business.inquirer.net/473940/e-commerce-tycoon-huang-tops-chinas-rich-list</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://business.inquirer.net/473940/e-commerce-tycoon-huang-tops-chinas-rich-list</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Beijing, China — E-commerce tycoon Colin Huang has become China&#8217;s richest man, an index showed Friday, capping an ascent for the former Google employee whose shopping site Temu has sucked in consumers with its low prices and all-powerful algorithms.</p>
<p>Huang, the founder of PDD Holdings &#8212; which owns Temu and Chinese retail app Pinduoduo &#8212; is now worth $48.6 billion, the Bloomberg Billionaires Index said.</p>
<p>He overtakes Zhong Shanshan, the boss of beverage company Nongfu Spring who had topped the list since April 2021, as the world&#8217;s 25th wealthiest person and the richest in China.</p>
<p><strong>READ: <a href="https://business.inquirer.net/446522/rise-of-fast-fashion-shein-temu-roils-global-air-cargo-industry#ixzz8iO16aYKQ">Rise of fast-fashion Shein, Temu roils global air cargo industry</a></strong></p>
<p>Close behind them is Ma Huateng, known as Pony Ma &#8212; head of tech giant Tencent, whose WeChat is often described as China&#8217;s &#8220;everything app&#8221;.</p>
<p>And in fourth place is Zhang Yiming, founder of Bytedance, which owns the massively popular TikTok video sharing platform.</p>
<p>Huang, born in 1980 in the eastern Chinese city of Hangzhou, was a teenage maths whizz and a former employee of Google China.</p>
<p>In 2015 he founded online shopping site Pinduoduo, which blossomed into one of China&#8217;s most successful e-commerce empires &#8212; rivalling Jack Ma&#8217;s Alibaba.</p>
<p>The app lured in consumers with huge discounts and a vast array of products, offering sometimes staggeringly low prices in a fiercely competitive field.</p>
<p>Its overseas iteration Temu launched in 2022 in the United States, where it amassed a loyal consumer base with ultra-low-cost goods made and shipped from China.</p>
<p><strong>READ: <a href="https://business.inquirer.net/460088/temu-owner-pinduoduo-says-triples-net-profit-in-first-quarter#ixzz8iO1KY22m">Temu owner Pinduoduo says triples net profit in first quarter</a></strong></p>
<p>Its success dovetailed with persistent high inflation that has pushed cost-conscious consumers to hunt for bargains, and it has since taken off in Europe, Latin America and elsewhere.</p>
<p>Despite only arriving in Europe last year, Temu has said it has on average around 75 million monthly active users in the region.</p>
<p>But its massive success had drawn accusations of unfair commercial practices and lax safety standards.</p>
<p>This year, consumer groups in Europe accused Temu of manipulating shoppers into spending more money, distorting their ability to make &#8220;free and informed decisions&#8221;.</p>
<p>And in April, South Korean regulators opened an investigation into Temu on suspicion of false advertising and unfair practices.</p>
<p>Last month, hundreds of merchants in China demonstrated at an affiliated office in the southern city of Guangzhou, alleging unfair treatment in the sale of their products on the platform.</p>
<p>But that has done little to dent the success of the firm, with PDD Holdings announcing in May that first-quarter net profit had more than tripled year-on-year.</p>
<p>The firm&#8217;s US-listed shares closed at $138.02 apiece on Thursday, giving it a market capitalisation of $191.68 billion.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
<imageUrl>https://business.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/Colin-Huang-Temu-scaled.jpg</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:41:28 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>San Marino consulate general partners with Bookmark, Inc. to publish &#8216;Pamilyang Papel&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://business.inquirer.net/473942/san-marino-consulate-general-partners-with-bookmark-inc-to-publish-pamilyang-papel</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://business.inquirer.net/473942/san-marino-consulate-general-partners-with-bookmark-inc-to-publish-pamilyang-papel</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Consulate General of the Republic of San Marino, represented by Consul General Jean Henri Lhuillier, and Bookmark Inc., headed by its President Maria Mercedes T. Rodrigo, have joined forces to publish and distribute the much-anticipated storybook, &#8220;Pamilyang Papel&#8221; (Paper Family). </span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This partnership highlights San Marino’s commitment to cultural and educational initiatives while delivering a heartfelt story that will reflect what the Republic of San Marino supports. This collaborative effort brings together the creative prowess of esteemed author Genaro R. Gojo Cruz and talented illustrator Christina L. Javier to deliver an engaging and culturally rich narrative.</span></p>
<p><b>A Unique Cultural Offering </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Pamilyang Papel&#8221; is more than just a children&#8217;s story; it is a narrative that brings to light the importance of family and the beauty of having one, as seen through the eyes of a young child named Miko. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With its touching story, the power of literature in bridging cultures and bringing stories that resonate with emotions shines through. The book is set to inspire readers of all ages with its touching narrative and captivating illustrations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More so, this literary collaboration between San Marino and Bookmark Inc. delivers a compelling story that will be cherished by readers of all ages as it underscores the importance of family. </span></p>
<p><b>Book Details </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Upon the finalization of the story and the high-resolution illustrations, “Pamilyang Papel” will be published and distributed under Bookmark Inc. Upon its release, both parties will ensure that the book reaches a wide audience. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With its upcoming release, San Marino Consul General and Cebuana Lhuillier President and CEO Jean Henri Lhuillier says, “The Republic of San Marino and the Philippines share a strong emphasis on the importance of family and community. By partnering with Bookmark Inc., and publishing “Pamilyang Papel”, we strengthen our shared values and our commitment to creating a better world for all children.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also sharing here excitement about the partnership, Bookmark Inc. President Maria Mercedes Rodrigo said, “We are thrilled to collaborate with the San Marino Consulate General to bring &#8216;Pamilyang Papel&#8217; to life. This partnership underscores our shared dedication to enriching children&#8217;s literature and promoting cultural understanding with a story that will surely touch readers of all ages.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><em><strong>ADVT. </strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>This article is brought to you by Bookmark Inc.</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[INQUIRER.net BrandRoom]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[BrandRoom]]></category>
<section><![CDATA[Advertorials]]></section>
<imageUrl>https://business.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/San-Marino-x-Bookmark-1-copy-scaled.jpg</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:30:48 +0000</updated>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mexico&#8217;s central bank clocks rise in inflation and cuts interest rates</title>
		<link>https://business.inquirer.net/473935/mexicos-central-bank-clocks-rise-in-inflation-and-cuts-interest-rates</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://business.inquirer.net/473935/mexicos-central-bank-clocks-rise-in-inflation-and-cuts-interest-rates</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>MEXICO CITY  — Analysts expressed shock Thursday at a decision by Mexico’s central bank to cut interest rates on the same day that official figures showed a sharp rise in domestic inflation. Almost without exception, central banks raise interest rates to make money more expensive, in order to discourage price increases.</p>
<p>But in a decision Thursday, the Bank of Mexico cut interest rates by 0.25% to 10.75%, even though inflation rose by over one percent to 5.57% in July. For most of this year, inflation has been moving further away from the central bank’s objective of 3%.</p>
<p><strong>READ: <a href="https://business.inquirer.net/458133/mexico-holds-interest-rate-steady-as-inflation-rises#ixzz8iNyZEAn6">Mexico holds interest rate steady as inflation rises</a></strong></p>
<p>The bank justified the move, saying there was a risk of lower growth in economic activity, and arguing that prices hikes occurred in more volatile sectors like energy and food.</p>
<p>But underlying inflation — the less volatile sectors that central banks watch especially closely for long-term trends — rose by 0.3% in July to just over 4%.</p>
<p>Moody’s Analytics Director Alfredo Coutiño called the decision &#8220;surprising,&#8221; and &#8220;totally inconsistent with inflationary conditions,” adding “the bank has taken an unnecessary risk.”</p>
<p>Coutiño said in a report that the rate cut “has the potential to increase pressures on the peso.” Mexico&#8217;s currency has suffered a significant drop against the U.S. dollar in recent weeks.</p>
<p>Gabriela Siller, director of economic analysis of the local financial group Banco Base, said “this could prove to be a policy error that could wind up damaging the reputation of the Bank of Mexico.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<source><![CDATA[Associated Press]]></source>
<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Inflationinterest rate cutsMexico]]></category>
<imageUrl>https://business.inquirer.net/files/2024/08/Mexicos-market-scaled.jpg</imageUrl>
<updated>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:21:08 +0000</updated>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>