<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>PugPig House Beautiful Bathroom Trends Feed</title>
    <link>https://howdyfeeds-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/Pugpig/pugpig_house_beautiful_uk_bathroom_trends.xml</link>
    <description>PugPig House Beautiful Bathroom Trends Feed</description>
    <atom:link rel="self"
      href="https://howdyfeeds-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/Pugpig/pugpig_house_beautiful_uk_bathroom_trends.xml"></atom:link>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 03:24:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HDM Syndication v2.0</generator>
    <copyright>(c) 2024 Hearst Digital Media</copyright>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 03:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[17 bathroom accessories to give your space a whole new look]]>
      </title>
      <link>https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g42801920/bathroom-accessories/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Stylish, fuss-free ways to elevate your washroom. </p> <p><strong><a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g41423790/best-bathroom-mirrors/" target="_blank">Bathroom</a> accessories and ornaments can be the deciding factor between a drab and fab washroom. From petite ensuites to large family bathrooms, selecting the right <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43245303/bathroom-cabinets/" target="_blank">bathroom</a> accessory helps to tie the room's overall look together and inject some extra personality into the space.</strong> </p><p>Accessories for a bathroom can be functional or purely ornamental, but the best options are a little bit of both. Unusual <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/lifestyle/storage/a29144268/small-bathroom-storage/" target="_blank">bathroom</a> ornaments with quirky designs help to create a visual focal point. On the other end of the scale, classic bathroom accessories help to create a polished look. </p><h2 class="body-h2">What are the most popular types of bathroom accessories? </h2><p>The most popular accessories and ornaments tie in with the top bathroom trends for 2024, including quiet luxury, scalloped (and rounded) shapes and natural textures. </p><p><strong></strong>'Live or faux plants add a touch of nature and freshness to the bathroom,' says Tracey Hague, director of <a href="https://wheresaintsgo.co.uk/" target="_blank">Where Saints Go</a>. 'Prints, photographs and paintings can add colour, texture and interest to a bathroom personalising the space. Decorative trays organise and display toiletries, soaps, and other items.'<br></p><h2 class="body-h2"><strong>How should I choose accessories for a bathroom?</strong></h2><p><strong></strong>'Consider the overall style of your bathroom, colours and patterns you have used and the size of your space,' says Tracey. 'Try to choose items that complement the overall design scheme. When styling bathroom ornaments, think about balance and proportion. Group small items for impact, and make sure large items don't overpower the space.'</p><p>If your bathroom is compact, choosing ornaments for a bathroom windowsill or shelf will make the best use of surface space. Multifunctional and versatile bathroom accessories (such as tumblers and trays) are also a great option.</p><p><em>From luxurious soap dispensers to ceramic trinket trays, keep reading to discover 17 on-trend and functional bathroom accessories for 2024. </em></p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g42801920/bathroom-accessories/</guid>
      <author>
        <![CDATA[Rosie Stagg]]>
      </author>
      <category>Home,App: Bathroom Trends,Decorate,Bathroom,Home Improvement,Interior Design,Shop Right Now</category>
      <source url="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g42801920/bathroom-accessories/">17 bathroom
      accessories to give your space a whole new look</source>
      <media:content
        url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/best-bathtroom-accessories-659d501860524.png?crop=1.00xw%3A1.00xh%3B0%2C0"
        type="image/png">
        <media:title type="html">
          <![CDATA[17 bathroom accessories to help style your space]]>
        </media:title>
        <media:description type="html">
          <![CDATA[Bathroom accessories can elevate the look of your washroom. Browse and shop our list of the best bathroom accessories and bathroom ornaments for 2024.]]>
        </media:description>
        <media:thumbnail
          url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/best-bathtroom-accessories-659d501860524.png?crop=1.00xw%3A1.00xh%3B0%2C0">
        </media:thumbnail>
        <media:credit>Oliver Bonas / Dunelm / Amazon</media:credit>
      </media:content>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1704802259-marble-electric-toothbrush-holder-659d37c05f648.png" /><figcaption><h3>1) Marble Electric Toothbrush Holder</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>marksandspencer.com</p><p><strong>£19.50</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.marksandspencer.com/marble-electric-toothbrush-holder/p/hbp60112105" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>This sophisticated toothbrush holder is crafted from fine marble and features two handy compartments. The holder features a smart, neutral tone, which we think makes it a brilliant fit for elegant bathrooms. </p><cite>Marks and Spencer</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1690471739-woven-black-bamboo-laundry-basket-64c28d2bce9d9.png" /><figcaption><h3>2) Woven Black Bamboo Laundry Basket</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>oliverbonas.com</p><p><strong>£55.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.oliverbonas.com/homeware/woven-black-bamboo-laundry-basket-356264" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>This petite laundry hamper is woven from natural bamboo to form a rounded shape. It combines natural-toned bamboo with a black Aztec-inspired pattern that wraps around the body of the basket and is finished with two round handles and a lid.</p><cite>Oliver Bonas</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1669997290-30747350.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>3) French Cane Bath Rack</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>dunelm.com</p><p><strong>£12.80</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.dunelm.com/product/french-cane-bath-rack-1000196468" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>We love the simple design of this bath rack, especially the cane detailing. Place the rack over your bathtub so you have all of your essentials at arm's reach. </p><cite>Dunelm</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1690472034-marble-soap-dish-64c28e5217836.png" /><figcaption><h3>4) Marble Soap Dish</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>marksandspencer.com</p><p><strong>£10.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.marksandspencer.com/marble-soap-dish/p/hbp22396851" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Add a sophisticated touch to your sink with this elegant marble soap dish. You can also say goodbye to soggy soap residue thanks to the draining holes in the bottom.</p><cite>Marks and Spencer</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1704802809-41pHzxsvBiL._SL500_.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>5) Hand Made Toilet Door Brass Sign</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>amazon.co.uk</p><p><strong>£8.90</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B00MK02BFA" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>This traditional brass door sign adds a classic touch to your interior. Plus, it lets guests know exactly which room they should head to. </p><cite>Amazon</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1676291289-30794452.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>6) Elements Lotion Dispenser</h3><p><strong>Elements</strong></p><p>dunelm.com</p><p><strong>£6.40</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.dunelm.com/product/elements-lotion-dispenser-1000211028" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>A burst of colour is just the thing to give your bathroom a whole new look, especially a shade as vibrant as this. Fill it to the brim with your favourite lotion and position it somewhere it'll catch the eye.</p><cite>Dunelm</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1704802419-PL_05_T36_5874D_P4_X_EC_1.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>7) Seville Feria Pure Cotton Fringed Towel</h3><p><strong>marks</strong></p><p>marksandspencer.com</p><p><strong>£6.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.marksandspencer.com/seville-feria-pure-cotton-fringed-towel/p/hbp60621639" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>This pure cotton bath towel from the M&S x Fired Earth collaboration is sure to add a unique touch to your bathroom. It's  inspired by the earthy colours of Seville. We love the added detail of the fringed ends.</p><cite>Marks and Spencer</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1675935831-original_concrete-wave-tray.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>8) Concrete Wave Tray</h3><p><strong>Storage & organisers</strong></p><p>notonthehighstreet.com</p><p><strong>$26.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.notonthehighstreet.com/concreteandcacti/product/concrete-wave-tray?referredBy=plp" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>The satisfying ripple design of this concrete tray gives it a wonderfully tactile finish. This bathroom ornament is ultra-versatile; use it to display perfumes, plants, or soaps.</p><cite>Not on the High Street</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1704803047-ernestine-bath-mat-659d3ab178f39.png" /><figcaption><h3>9) Ernestine Bath Mat</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>Anthropologie</p><p><strong>£38.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.anthropologie.com/en-gb/shop/ernestine-bath-mat2" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>This plush bath mat proves that functional bathroom accessories don't have to sacrifice aesthetics to work well in your home. We love the combination of blue and white, as well as the playfully-shaped edges. </p><cite>Anthropologie</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1676290817-touch-waste-can-1676290802.png" /><figcaption><h3>10) Umbra Touch Waste Can</h3><p><strong>Umbra</strong></p><p>amazon.co.uk</p><p><strong>£34.05</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B00HY8H5KE" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>A decent bathroom bin is a must-have accessory in any home. We particularly like this understated design, which is both functional and sleek.</p><cite>Amazon</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1675935209-A02932_SU22_2_F.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>11) Mango-Wood Hurricane Candle Holder</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>thewhitecompany.com</p><p><strong>£35.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.thewhitecompany.com/uk/Mango-Wood-Hurricane-Candle-Holder/p/A02932?swatch=Clear" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>For a tranquil and spa-like bathroom experience, candles are a must. This mango wood candle holder will keep your favourite pillar candles safe from being knocked over (and protected from chilly drafts, too). We love its subtle, elegant design.</p><cite>The White Company</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1639086262-vardagen-jar-with-lid-clear-glass__0713736_pe729735_s5.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>12) Vardagen Jar</h3><p><strong>ikea</strong></p><p>ikea.com.uk</p><p><strong>£4.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.ikea.com/gb/en/p/vardagen-jar-with-lid-clear-glass-00291928/" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>A clear glass jar is a versatile bathroom ornament that you can use for a myriad of purposes. It's also a timeless option that won't date as you adapt your interior over the years.</p><cite>Ikea</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1704803248-1692136_4.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>13) Crocodile Green Ceramic Soap Dish</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>oliverbonas.com</p><p><strong>£12.50</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.oliverbonas.com/homeware/crocodile-green-ceramic-soap-dish-355905" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>In a shiny green glaze, this charming crocodile soap dish has a textured finish and a lovely sculptural quality. One of our favourite bathroom accessories on the list, place this on your sink and your bathroom is sure to get compliments. </p><cite>Oliver Bonas</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1690472326-30764981.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>14) Bubble Glass Amber Tumbler</h3><p><strong>Dunelm</strong></p><p>dunelm.com</p><p><strong>£4.80</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.dunelm.com/product/bubble-glass-amber-tumbler-1000199786" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>This playful bubble tumbler is great for storing bathroom goods such as toothbrushes and makeup brushes. We love the amber tint. </p><cite>Dunelm</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1690473172-jesmonite-towel-ring-marbled-with-leather-strap-64c292c4458c5.png" /><figcaption><h3>15) Jesmonite Towel Ring Marbled With Leather Strap</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>notonthehighstreet.com</p><p><strong>£30.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.notonthehighstreet.com/misshandled/product/jesmonite-marbled-towel-ring-leather-strap" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>With a beautiful hand-cut leather strap, each of these marbled towel rings has its own unique marbling pattern. We think it's just the accessory you need to add some colour to your bathroom.</p><cite>Not on the High Street</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1690473460-30807041.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>16) Wire Toilet Butler</h3><p><strong>Dunelm</strong></p><p>dunelm.com</p><p><strong>£8.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.dunelm.com/product/essentials-toilet-butler-1000211033" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>A practical bathroom accessory, but an essential nonetheless, keep your toilet rolls tidy and organised with this simple toilet roll holder. </p><cite>Dunelm</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1704803472-71bMYoBANML.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>17) Corner Shower Caddy 2-Pack</h3><p><strong>Yazoni</strong></p><p>amazon.co.uk</p><p><strong>£16.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0B8D8SJQK" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Keep your toiletries organised and easy to reach with this corner shower caddy. The attachment process doesn't require drilling, so there isn't any damage to the wall – perfect for renters.</p><cite>Amazon</cite></figcaption></figure>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[13 towel rail ideas to maximise space in your bathroom]]>
      </title>
      <link>https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43177593/towel-rails/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>All you need to know about buying the right towel rail for your bathroom.</p> <p><strong>When it comes to contemporary <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g27912693/bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">bathroom design</a>, towel rails are often preferred over standard radiators – and we can see why. There’s nothing better than stepping out of the shower and wrapping yourself in a warm, fluffy towel. Towel rails are a smart, space-saving addition to bathrooms, offering not only practicality but a sleek, designer look. Plus, the warmth from a heated towel rail provides extra heat in your <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a42306993/bathroom-trends/" target="_blank">bathroom</a>, creating a cosy environment on even the chilliest of days.</strong></p><p>'Bathrooms tend to have limited space available but the last thing you want in the colder months is for the room to be freezing,' says Simon Morris, marketing manager at <a href="https://www.theradiatorcompany.co.uk/" target="_blank">The Radiator Company</a>. 'If you'd love the comfort of toasty warm towels when you step out from the bath, and would like to keep the chill off the room as a whole, consider investing in a towel rail.<br></p><p>'Space is often a consideration when choosing a towel rail but you also need to ensure you have enough hanging space on the rail to accommodate everyone's towels. One of the first things you need to ask yourself is how many people use the bathroom, and how many <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/lifestyle/shopping/g33978284/luxury-towels/" target="_blank">towels</a> are you likely to have?'</p><p>When investing in a towel rail, watch out for where the wall hanging brackets are located, Simon warns: 'Brackets often sit between the cross bars at the back and limit the hanging space down the middle for damp towels. Look for ranges with brackets on the outside collectors to increase hanging space.'</p><h2 class="body-h2">Types of towel rails</h2><p>From ladder towel rails to traditional cast iron towel rails, and even compact designs for a smaller bathroom, there's a myriad of styles on offer. Towel rails also come in various forms, such as electric, dual fuel and even freestanding. If you're considering a heated towel warmer, you’ll need to think about what power source you’ll be using to heat it. There are three main power sources for heated towel rails:</p><ol><li><strong>Electric towel rails</strong> are powered by your mains electricity, making them a practical option if you don't want to make any changes to your existing pipework. Electric towel warmers work whether your central heating is on or not – ideal for heating your bathroom in the summer months when the heating isn't on.</li><li><strong>Plumbed towel rails</strong> work alongside your central heating. This means that when the central heating is on, your towel rail will come on at the same time. If you opt for a plumbed towel radiator, make sure you choose one with similar pipe sizing to your existing radiator to save the hassle of reworking the pipes. </li><li><strong>Dual fuel towel rails </strong>offer the best of both worlds as they are powered by both electricity and your central heating. This means you can heat your towel rail both in the winter alongside your central heating as well as in the summer months when the heating is off.</li></ol><h2 class="body-h2">Best towel rails for 2024 </h2>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43177593/towel-rails/</guid>
      <author>
        <![CDATA[Laura Hill]]>
      </author>
      <category>Home,Most Popular,App: Bathroom Trends,Decorate,App: Bathroom How-Tos,Bathroom,Home Improvement,Shop
        Right Now</category>
      <source url="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43177593/towel-rails/">13 towel rail ideas to
      maximise space in your bathroom</source>
      <media:content
        url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/towel-rails-6405fea781cf4.png?crop=1.00xw%3A1.00xh%3B0%2C0"
        type="image/png">
        <media:title type="html">
          <![CDATA[Maximise your space with a towel rail]]>
        </media:title>
        <media:description type="html">
          <![CDATA[Towel rails are a smart, space-saving addition to bathrooms, offering not only practicality but a sleek, designer look.]]>
        </media:description>
        <media:thumbnail
          url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/towel-rails-6405fea781cf4.png?crop=1.00xw%3A1.00xh%3B0%2C0">
        </media:thumbnail>
        <media:keywords>Most Popular</media:keywords>
        <media:credit>The Radiator Company</media:credit>
      </media:content>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1677855120-vertical-straight-towel-rail-6402094cd9939.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>1) Vertical Ladder Towel Rail</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>www.wayfair.co.uk</p><p><strong>£88.21</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.wayfair.co.uk/diy-plumbing/pdp/k-rad-vertical-straight-towel-rail-krad1082.html" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Fans of <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/kitchen/g43117713/industrial-kitchen/" target="_blank">industrial</a> decor will love this black ladder towel rail. Designed with practicality in mind, there are several size options available to offer space for multiple towels. Pair with white brick tiles for a contemporary look.</p><cite>Wayfair</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1677855913-30748009.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>2) Fulton Wood Black Floor Towel Rail</h3><p><strong>Dunelm</strong></p><p>dunelm.com</p><p><strong>£42.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.dunelm.com/product/fulton-wood-black-floor-towel-rail-1000195002" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Not everyone wants to go through the hassle of installing a heated towel rail. Freestanding towel rails maximise <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/lifestyle/storage/g42568806/storage-baskets/" target="_blank">storage</a> in your bathroom whilst offering a sleek and stylish look. This contemporary towel rail is designed with four sections, providing ample space to hang towels.</p><cite>Dunelm</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1677856694-e1b94b4e-87d2-4663-8b34-7b4dba5dbef1.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>3) Stone Grey Heated Towel Rail</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>victoriaplum.com</p><p><strong>£74.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://victoriaplum.com/product/the-heating-co-bali-stone-grey-heated-towel-rail" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Featuring a panelled design and a stone grey painted finish, this heated towel rail from Victoria Plum complements ultra modern bathroom spaces. The dual heating element can heat up a whole room – as well as towels – making it an ideal option for family bathrooms.</p><cite>Victoria Plum</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678110405-terma-warp-s-heated-towel-rail-matt-orange-1110-x-500.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>4) Matt Orange Heated Towel Rail</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>plumbworld.co.uk</p><p><strong>£294.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.plumbworld.co.uk/terma-warp-s-heated-towel-rail-matt-orange-1110-x-500-150-1269493" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Who said bathrooms have to be cold, sterile and white? Add a splash of colour to your bathroom with this punchy orange towel rail. The asymmetric design not only offers practicality when hanging towels but acts as a striking focal point in the room. </p><cite>Plumbworld</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1677860313-51WEiMBwhL._SL500_.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>5) Wall Mounted Bathroom Towel Rail</h3><p><strong>SAYAYO</strong></p><p>amazon.co.uk</p><p><strong>£39.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B09CYZ641X" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>With its double towel bars, upper towel rack and wall-mounted design, this chic gold towel rail is the ultimate space-saver. Simply mount on the wall with fixing screws and add your favourite <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/lifestyle/shopping/g33978284/luxury-towels/" target="_blank">fluffy towels</a>. The heavy duty design means you can place your large bath sheets on top without having to worry.</p><cite>Amazon</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1677856312-238539100.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>6) ANYDAY Bamboo Towel Stand</h3><p><strong>John Lewis ANYDAY</strong></p><p>johnlewis.com</p><p><strong>£55.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.johnlewis.com/john-lewis-anyday-bamboo-towel-stand/p4875463" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Achieve botanical bliss in your bathroom with a freestanding bamboo towel rail. Pair this minimalist number from John Lewis with trailing plants and earthy materials for a nature-inspired look. The freestanding rail comes with two rungs that can support two or three towels.</p><cite>johnlewis.com</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1677859179-t613ws_ls_1000_a.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>7) White Traditional Heated Towel Rail</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>bestheating.com</p><p><strong>£267.96</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.bestheating.com/milano-elizabeth-white-traditional-heated-towel-rail-930mm-x-450mm-74331" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>A perfect pairing for homes with a traditional feel, this cast iron-style heated towel rail exudes elegance and class. The white column insert gives this towel warmer a period look, whilst the brass heating elements provide snuggly warmth throughout your bathroom. Style with <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/lifestyle/shopping/a32993311/shopping-vintage-furniture/" target="_blank">vintage</a> bathroom accessories to complete the look.</p><cite>Best Heating</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1677861617-71164111_1.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>8) Over the Door Hanging Towel Rail</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>manomano.co.uk</p><p><strong>£13.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.manomano.co.uk/p/bathroom-solutions-hanging-door-towel-rack-metal-black---black-33486485" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Featuring a sleek industrial metal frame, this over-the-door hanging towel rail from Mano Mano is ideal for small bathrooms that lack floor space. With a four bar design, it can hang enough towels for the whole family. Simply hang over a door up to a thickness of 5cm and it's ready to be used.</p><cite>Mano Mano</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1704975605-scene.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>9) Majestic Brushed Brass Towel Rail</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>royalbathrooms.co.uk</p><p><strong>£279.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://royalbathrooms.co.uk/majestic-500-x-1200mm-brushed-brass-towel-rail-curved-ladder-vi-12-50-bb.html" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Incorporating brushed brass in your bathroom is a simple way to <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/lifestyle/shopping/g46201149/decor-upgrades/" target="_blank">make it look expensive</a> – as proven here by this luxury heated rail from Royal Bathrooms. It has 12 rounded bars to hang plenty of towels and even comes with a five year guarantee.</p><cite>Royal Bathrooms</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678096940-flomasta-black-vertical-curved-towel-radiator-w-400mm-x-h-700mm~5059340502359_01c.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>10) Flomasta Black Vertical Curved Towel Radiator</h3><p><strong>New</strong></p><p>diy.com</p><p><strong>£37.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.diy.com/departments/flomasta-black-vertical-curved-towel-radiator-w-400mm-x-h-700mm/5063022022301_BQ.prd" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Cool and contemporary, this black towel warmer features clean lines and curved edges to create an ultra-modern look. Plus, it's powerful enough to heat the whole room.</p><cite>B&Q</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678100325-8326030_R_Z003A_UC497431.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>11) Traditional 5 Tier Freestanding Towel Rail</h3><p><strong>Argos Home</strong></p><p>argos.co.uk</p><p><strong>£18.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.argos.co.uk/product/8326030" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Amplify your bathroom storage with a five-tiered towel rail. This affordable option from Argos is designed with elegant curves to complement a <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/renovate/homes-makeovers/a40358078/emma-rossi-traditional-family-home-eclectic/" target="_blank">traditional</a> bathroom scheme. Practical as well as charming, it can be easily moved around the room to create more floor space. </p><cite>Argos</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678101232-GPID_1100086010_00.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>12) Mayfair Chrome Towel Radiator</h3><p><strong>Mayfair</strong></p><p>wickes.co.uk</p><p><strong>£356.40</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.wickes.co.uk/Towelrads-Mayfair-Chrome-Towel-Radiator---500mm---Various-Heights-Available/p/9000259533" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Featuring a versatile design that can be hung left or right, this modern towel warmer provides ample space for hanging towels. It has a unique singular vertical bar shape, making it easier to hang towels in a hurry. It's an ideal option if you're after a high-end, luxury look.</p><cite>Wickes</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678109835-htrrf040060ae_ls_1000_new.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>13) Milano Anthracite Electric Towel Rail</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>bigbathroomshop.co.uk</p><p><strong>£126.39</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.bigbathroomshop.co.uk/milano-artle-electric-anthracite-straight-heated-towel-rail-600mm-x-400mm-91166" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Redesigning your small bathroom and unsure if you can incorporate a towel rail? You'll be pleased to know that even small bathrooms with limited wall space can have the luxury of a towel rail. Compact towel warmers are an essential for small bathrooms, with this contemporary anthracite option sizing up at just 60cm x 40cm.</p><cite>The Big Bathroom Shop</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678098050-athena-bdo-stock-base.png" /><figcaption><h3>14) Athena Horizontal Towel Rail</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>theradiatorcompany.co.uk</p><p><strong>£688.80</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.theradiatorcompany.co.uk/athena-bdo-towel-rail-stock" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>If you're revamping your bathroom and want to create a space with wow factor, opt for a horizontal towel rail. Designed with a slimline profile, this steel grey radiator provides a contemporary storage solution that will maximise space under windows and over baths.</p><cite>The Radiator Company</cite></figcaption></figure>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[15 black bathroom accessories for a contemporary finish]]>
      </title>
      <link>https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43891009/black-bathroom-accessories/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Make a statement with these bold designs.</p> <p><strong>Dark accessories are a bold choice in bathrooms, providing much-needed contrast to the </strong><strong><strong><strong>sterile-looking spaces we're often accustomed to</strong></strong></strong><strong>. Incorporating black bathroom accessories in particular is an easy way to add</strong><strong> depth, drama, and a contemporary finish without committing to a full black <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g27912693/bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">bathroom design</a> (although this <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a23705794/black-gold-bathroom-jess-hurrell/" target="_blank">black and gold bathroom by interiors blogger Jess Hurrell </a></strong><strong>will forever serve as inspiration if you're ready to make that leap).</strong><br></p><p>When it comes to black bathroom accessories, the benefits are tenfold, ticking many boxes from a practical point of view, way beyond the understated <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a43144474/luxury-bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">luxe aesthetic</a> it offers in abundance.</p><p>'Matt black has become one of the top finishes favoured by interior designers and homeowners alike, especially when it comes to bathroom brassware and accessories,' says Richard Ticehurst, brand expert at <a href="https://www.brittonbathrooms.com/" target="_blank">Britton Bathroom</a>. 'It's extremely versatile and complements a myriad of colour schemes, materials, and interior styles. Unlike the shiny surface of chrome or stainless steel, matt black is easier to clean and maintain as the surface is less prone to water spots, fingerprints, and smudges – making it ideal for busy family bathrooms.'<br></p><p><br></p><h2 class="body-h2">How to style black bathroom accessories</h2><p>A crisp white bathroom with a metro <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g38915455/bathroom-tile-ideas/" target="_blank">tiled wall</a>? Choose black accents to achieve a pared-back monochromatic look. Alternatively, black bathroom accessories against a sage green wall will ground an already-calming bathroom scheme, or use black accents to elevate a colourful backdrop from soft rose to terracotta.</p><p>'In bathrooms where lighter colours dominate and the instinct is to go bright, matt black accessories create a striking contrast and add a different dimension, drawing the eye to certain elements of the space,' adds Richard. But to soften the sometimes harsh lines and dark hues that black bathroom accessories can present, offset this with different finishes and textures. For example, contrasting black and gold accessories or those with <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/looks/g43771299/dark-wood/" target="_blank">wooden accents</a> will always work a treat.</p><p>Here, we'll look at some of the best ways to incorporate black into your bathroom design without weighing it down, helping you to create a space that is every bit as luxe as it is contemporary. From toothbrush holders to towel racks, we’ve pulled together an edit of some of our favourite black bathroom accessories.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 08:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43891009/black-bathroom-accessories/
      </guid>
      <author>
        <![CDATA[Laura Hill]]>
      </author>
      <category>Home,Most Popular,App: Bathroom Trends,Decorate,Bathroom,Interior Design,Shop Right Now</category>
      <source url="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43891009/black-bathroom-accessories/">15 black
      bathroom accessories for a contemporary finish</source>
      <media:content
        url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/black-bathroom-accessories-6464bdea51734.png?crop=1.00xw%3A1.00xh%3B0%2C0"
        type="image/png">
        <media:title type="html">
          <![CDATA[15 black bathroom accessories you need right now]]>
        </media:title>
        <media:description type="html">
          <![CDATA[From towel racks to vanity units, a black accent provides a sleek and sophisticated edge to bathrooms. Get ready to make a statement with these bold accessories.]]>
        </media:description>
        <media:thumbnail
          url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/black-bathroom-accessories-6464bdea51734.png?crop=1.00xw%3A1.00xh%3B0%2C0">
        </media:thumbnail>
        <media:keywords>Most Popular</media:keywords>
        <media:credit>Rockett St George/Dunelm</media:credit>
      </media:content>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684153788-30712635.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>1) Elements Black Extra Large Curved Ladder</h3><p><strong>Quick Delivery</strong></p><p>dunelm.com</p><p><strong>£45.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.dunelm.com/product/elements-black-extra-large-curved-ladder-1000180628" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Swap your standard towel hooks for a black towel ladder for a seriously stylish bathroom aesthetic. This extra large towel ladder from Dunelm sits close to the wall, taking up minimal floor space. It also has rubber feet, so you don't have to worry about it slipping.</p><cite>Dunelm</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684153683-240989191.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>2) John Lewis ANYDAY Matt Black Toilet Brush</h3><p><strong>John Lewis ANYDAY</strong></p><p>johnlewis.com</p><p><strong>£15.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.johnlewis.com/john-lewis-anyday-toilet-brush-matt-black/p6118712" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Simple, sleek and affordable, this matt black toilet brush is made from resin so it's super easy to wipe clean. You can create a coordinated look (without breaking the bank) by matching it with other matt black accessories in the ANYDAY range, such as this <a href="https://www.johnlewis.com/john-lewis-anyday-matt-finish-soap-pump/black/p3931097" target="_blank">soap pump</a> and <a href="https://www.johnlewis.com/john-lewis-anyday-matt-black-toilet-roll-holder/p4891340" target="_blank">toilet roll holder</a>.</p><cite>John Lewis</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684154226-terma-warp-t-bold-black-flat-towel-warmer-w-500mm-x-h-1110mm-5901804491900-02i-bq-64622764bdb49.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>3) Terma Warp T Bold Black Flat Towel Warmer</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>diy.com</p><p><strong>£348.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.diy.com/departments/terma-warp-t-bold-black-flat-towel-warmer-w-500mm-x-h-1110mm/5901804491900_BQ.prd" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>If you're planning a contemporary bathroom reno, replacing your standard radiator with a black towel warmer is an essential upgrade. We love this Terma towel warmer in particular as it has double layered bars at the front and back, providing higher heat outputs and more space to hang towels.</p><cite>B&Q</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684154787-1601850_00_640x640.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>4) Noah Black Bin</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>housebeautiful.co.uk</p><p><strong>£32.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://housebeautiful.co.uk/products/noah-bin-black?%2F%3Futm_source=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.housebeautiful.com%2Fuk" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Don't want to go the full hog with a black bathroom design? The effortlessly stylish Noah bin allows you to experiment with darker tones whilst still incorporating warm, natural elements. With its two-tone black and bamboo detailing, we think it'd make a great addition to bathrooms with an industrial-meets-Scandi feel. </p><cite>House Beautiful Marketplace</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684153840-30711388.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>5) Elements Matt Black 3 Tier Caddy</h3><p><strong>Quick Delivery</strong></p><p>dunelm.com</p><p><strong>£25.60</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.dunelm.com/product/elements-matt-black-3-tier-caddy-1000180347" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Here's a bathroom storage solution that boasts contemporary style <em>and </em>functionality. Personally, we'd just use it for styling a few decorative items, but there are three spacious shelves if you'd prefer to pile up all of your bathroom necessities. </p><cite>Dunelm</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684155396-heinecker-790mm-wall-mounted-bathroom-vanity-with-vanity-top-64622bce9818b.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>6) Ebern Designs Heinecker Wall Mounted Vanity Unit</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>wayfair.co.uk</p><p><strong>£73.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.wayfair.co.uk/diy-plumbing/pdp/ebern-designs-heinecker-790mm-wall-hung-single-vanity-unit-u004148101.html" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>For extra storage with an industrial flair, opt for this black wall-mounted vanity unit. It's made of powder-coated iron for ultimate durability and easy cleaning. Roll up your favourite fluffy towels and pop them on the shelf alongside fancy soaps and a reed diffuser. </p><cite>Wayfair</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684153589-9504851_R_Z001A.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>7) Habitat 3 Piece Soft Touch Black Accessory Set </h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>habitat.co.uk</p><p><strong>£16.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.habitat.co.uk/product/9504851" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>If you've got a soft spot for black like we have, you need this soft touch bathroom accessory set in your life. Consisting of a soap dish, soap dispenser and mug, this super affordable set will add a cool, contemporary touch to your bathroom. Each piece is made from ceramic but finished with a smooth touch.</p><cite>Habitat</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684155482-61VZZAdrUL.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>8) Niffgaff Black Freestanding Toilet Roll Holder</h3><p><strong>niffgaff</strong></p><p>amazon.co.uk</p><p><strong>£16.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B09NHSPYN5" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>We love freestanding bathroom accessories; they're easy to install (no drilling needed!) which makes them ideal for renters or anti-DIYers. Plus, they're bang on trend. This matt black toilet roll holder is made from durable stainless steel and features a folding design that can fit up to four toilet rolls.  </p><cite>Amazon</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684162204-239801696alt2-6462468d70cca.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>9) John Lewis ANYDAY Matt Black Reversible Bathroom Shelf</h3><p><strong>John Lewis ANYDAY</strong></p><p>johnlewis.com</p><p><strong>£25.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.johnlewis.com/john-lewis-anyday-matt-black-reversible-bathroom-shelf/p5329689" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Bathrooms are the one room in the house that tend to look plain – often with lots of bare wall space and little decoration. If this sounds familiar, adding some bathroom wall shelves could be your answer. With its clean lines and wire shapes, this matt black wall shelf will add contemporary detail to your bathroom. </p><cite>John Lewis</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684162031-t38wiypycz2yedboo0xiv-646245bf79bad.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>10) Black Iron Bathroom Mirror With Shelf</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>rockettstgeorge.co.uk</p><p><strong>$85.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.rockettstgeorge.co.uk/black-iron-bathroom-mirror-with-shelf.html" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Every bathroom needs a mirror, and we are obsessed with this iron number from Rockett St George. A must-have for industrial interiors, this sleek mirror has been designed with a wire shelf to store all of your bathroom essentials. It's the perfect bathroom centrepiece (if we do say so ourselves).</p><cite>Rockett St George</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684154314-bt0041bl_ls_1000_1.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>11) Milano Nero Mono Basin Mixer Tap</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>bigbathroomshop.co.uk</p><p><strong>£79.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.bigbathroomshop.co.uk/milano-nero-mono-basin-mixer-tap-black-75475" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>This designer basin tap is more of a bathroom fitting than an accessory, but we just had to include it. The matt black design makes it a perfect match for your matt black accessories (and let's face it, it trumps a chrome tap any day). Team with other items from the <a href="https://www.bigbathroomshop.co.uk/catalogsearch/result/?q=milano+nero" target="_blank">Milano Nero</a> collection for a coordinated monochrome aesthetic.</p><cite>Big Bathroom Shop</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684154932-5535082_00_640x640.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>12) Cassidy Glass Soap Dispenser in Gold/Black</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>housebeautiful.co.uk</p><p><strong>£18.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://housebeautiful.co.uk/products/cassidy-glass-soap-dispenser-gold-black?%2F%3Futm_source=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.housebeautiful.com%2Fuk" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Add a little bit of luxe to your black bathroom aesthetic by incorporating gold accents. The tinted gold finish of this soap dispenser acts as the perfect contrast to daring black tones, creating an elegant yet contemporary feel in your bathroom. We're adding the rest of the <a href="https://housebeautiful.co.uk/search?q=cassidy&type=product&options%5Bprefix%5D=last%2F%3Futm_source%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.housebeautiful.com%2Fuk" target="_blank">Cassidy</a> range to our cart, as well.</p><cite>House Beautiful Marketplace</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684162546-57827966_001_b.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>13) Bridgette Storage Bath Rack</h3><p><strong>Anthropologie</strong></p><p>anthropologie.com.uk</p><p><strong>€98.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.anthropologie.com/en-gb/shop/bridgette-storage-bath-rack" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Take a moment for yourself by running a hot bath, lighting a scented candle and propping up a good book on a bath rack. This wire bath rack is the perfect accompaniment to a relaxing bath, and it looks the part, too.</p><cite>Anthropologie</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684153898-hmgoepprod.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>14) Earthenware Toothbrush Mug</h3><p><strong>H&M</strong></p><p>hm.com.uk</p><p><strong>£3.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www2.hm.com/en_gb/productpage.1069184003.html" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Made from 1oo per cent clay, this earthenware toothbrush mug is an essential for lovers of natural materials. The streamlined design gives this piece a beautifully minimalist look, and the glazed finish makes it look much more expensive than it is.</p><cite>H&M</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1684154587-merano-thermostatic-mixer-shower-square-bar-valve-with-square-drench-adjustable-heads-black.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>15) Merano Thermostatic Square Bar Mixer Shower</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>plumbworld.co.uk</p><p><strong>£139.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.plumbworld.co.uk/merano-thermostatic-mixer-shower-square-bar-valve-with-square-drench-adjustable-heads-black-18174-1262338" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>This is arguably another bathroom fitting rather than an accessory, but it really finishes off the room. The contemporary square bars and large square shower head are enough to transform your whole bathroom from old and drab to contemporary and fab. Unless you're super savvy with bathroom fittings, you'll probably need a plumber to fit it, but it's worth the hassle. </p><cite>Plumbworld</cite></figcaption></figure>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[15 bathroom cabinet ideas to inspire your bathroom makeover]]>
      </title>
      <link>https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43245303/bathroom-cabinets/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Create a clutter-free space with these beautiful bathroom cabinets.</p> <p><strong>It’s easy to spend all the time in the world tidying and styling your <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/living-room/g29292200/grey-living-room-ideas/" target="_blank">living areas</a>, yet one of the most important rooms in the home (the bathroom) tends to get neglected. If your <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g27912693/bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">bathroom</a> is looking and feeling like an afterthought, sometimes adding or upgrading furniture, such as new bathroom cabinets, is all it takes to transform the space from dull and drab to sparkling new. </strong> </p><h3 class="body-h3"><strong>Before you start</strong></h3><p>If you’ve got your eye on some chic new bathroom cabinet designs, it might be tempting to buy the first ones you like the look of, but there are lots of things to consider first. Remember, in its most functional form, a bathroom cabinet is ultimately a storage essential, enabling you to corral toiletries and the like. When combined with material, colour choice and finishing touches, aesthetically it aids in the overall style and character of your bathroom scheme. So before you look at the styles and <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/walls/g42965862/farrow-ball-new-paint-colours-buy/" target="_blank">colours</a> of your new bathroom cabinets, start off by thinking about the size of your bathroom and what you actually <em>need </em>in the room.</p><p><br></p><h3 class="body-h3"><strong>Consider the size and shape of your bathroom</strong></h3><p>Ask yourself: how much storage space do I need? Start by grabbing a tape measure and accurately measuring the size and shape of your bathroom. Note down the length and width of the space, being mindful of any odd-shaped corners or nooks. Once you've got your measurements written down, take a look at the cabinet sizes you’ve seen online and compare them. Don’t forget to check the depth of the cabinet to make sure it won't stick out too much.</p><p>Once you've found cabinets that fit your space, consider how many you’ll need – this will largely depend on how much you've got to store away.</p><h3 class="body-h3"><strong>Types of bathroom cabinet</strong></h3><p>From vanity units to corner cabinets, there are so many types of bathroom cabinets available that it can become rather confusing when trying to choose the right one for your space. Take a look at the different types of cabinets below to understand which ones will work best in your bathroom, then create a quick sketch of the space to visually determine how they will look. </p><h4 class="body-h4">1.     Vanity units</h4><p>Available in both wall-hung and freestanding options, vanity units are a type of bathroom cabinet that combine a basin and a storage cupboard in one piece of furniture. Swap your traditional basin pedestal for a vanity unit if you're looking for a stylish storage option that takes up no extra space in the bathroom.</p><h4 class="body-h4">2.     Toilet units</h4><p>Back to wall toilet units are an ideal option for small cloakrooms or en-suites where space is limited. Not only do they conceal the cistern, providing a neat and tidy look, but they can also offer extra storage. If you’re looking for somewhere to store toiletries without taking up floor space, opt for a toilet unit with an added cupboard or drawer.</p><h4 class="body-h4">3.     Mirrored bathroom cabinets</h4><p>A mirrored cabinet is a type of bathroom cabinet that is often wall-hung above a sink. Mirrored cabinets act as handy storage for toiletries such as face wash, toothbrushes and medicines. They combine two needs into one by offering both easy to reach storage and added contemporary style.</p><h4 class="body-h4">4.     Tall bathroom cabinets</h4><p>Tall bathroom cabinets are an essential storage option for family households or homes with larger bathrooms. With both freestanding and wall-hung options available, tall bathroom cabinets provide ample vertical space for storing a range of toiletries and even towels. If you have a smaller bathroom, choose a slimline tall cabinet to free up floor space.</p><h4 class="body-h4">5.     Corner bathroom cabinets</h4><p>Corner cabinets are a popular choice when it comes to bathroom storage as they take up less space than a traditional cabinet. Corner cabinets are compact in size, making them a vital storage solution for smaller en-suite spaces. For ultimate space-saving, choose a wall-hung corner cabinet. </p><h4 class="body-h4">6.     Fitted bathroom cabinets</h4><p>If you’re looking for an all-in-one storage solution, consider fitted bathroom furniture. Fitted bathroom cabinets can be attached to the wall and floor to provide heaps of space for toiletries and towels. Plus, fitted furniture provides a sleek, unified look throughout your whole bathroom. </p><h3 class="body-h3"><strong>Choose your colour and style</strong></h3><p>Once you’ve decided on the type of bathroom cabinet(s) you need, it’s time to choose a colour and style. Whether your existing interior decor is <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/renovate/homes-makeovers/a40358078/emma-rossi-traditional-family-home-eclectic/" target="_blank">traditional</a>, contemporary, <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/windows/a40866380/5-ways-to-create-a-maximalist-look/" target="_blank">maximalist</a> or minimalist, there are a huge range of bathroom cabinet styles to suit. If traditional is your thing, opt for shaker-style bathroom cabinets in a deep navy blue or forest green. Alternatively, white and grey handleless options provide a smooth, clean design to complement contemporary bathroom schemes.</p><p><strong>Ready to start your bathroom makeover? Discover the best bathroom cabinet ideas for your space below.</strong></p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43245303/bathroom-cabinets/</guid>
      <author>
        <![CDATA[Laura Hill]]>
      </author>
      <category>Home,Most Popular,App: Bathroom Trends,Decorate,Bathroom,Interior Design,Shop Right Now</category>
      <source url="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43245303/bathroom-cabinets/">15 bathroom cabinet
      ideas to inspire your bathroom makeover</source>
      <media:content
        url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-cabinets-6408b465107a7.png?crop=1.00xw%3A1.00xh%3B0%2C0"
        type="image/png">
        <media:title type="html">
          <![CDATA[15 beautiful bathroom cabinet ideas]]>
        </media:title>
        <media:description type="html">
          <![CDATA[From vanity units to corner cabinets, create a clutter-free space with these beautiful bathroom cabinet ideas.]]>
        </media:description>
        <media:thumbnail
          url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-cabinets-6408b465107a7.png?crop=1.00xw%3A1.00xh%3B0%2C0">
        </media:thumbnail>
        <media:keywords>Most Popular</media:keywords>
        <media:credit>Dunelm/Homebase</media:credit>
      </media:content>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678283881-bfmo1202gob_ls_1000_a_new.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>1) Golden Oak Wall Hung Vanity Unit</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>bigbathroomshop.co.uk</p><p><strong>£399.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.bigbathroomshop.co.uk/milano-oxley-golden-oak-800mm-wall-hung-vanity-unit-with-basin-75175" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Free up floor space with a wall-hung vanity unit. Made with engineered wood, this vanity unit offers a natural yet <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/walls/a34270213/painting-techniques-home-trends/" target="_blank">contemporary</a> look. The push to open soft close drawer provides lots of space for toiletries, and there's even the option to add an LED furniture light.</p><cite>Big Bathroom Shop</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678876327-89221797_1.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>2) The Bath Co. Green TraditionalBathroom Vanity Unit</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>manomano.co.uk</p><p><strong>£582.75</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.manomano.co.uk/catalogue/p/the-bath-co-ascot-green-floorstanding-vanity-unit-and-ceramic-basin-800mm-67100675" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Make a statement with a gorgeous <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a2255/bathroom-decorating-ideas-greenery/" target="_blank">green</a> vanity unit. This rustic green freestanding cabinet has been cleverly designed with panelled doors and an open bottom shelf to store neatly folded towels. It comes complete with a classic countertop sink to finish off the luxury bathroom look.</p><cite>Mano Mano</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678282838-b91225fa-3f3c-448c-8316-e9a101cde795.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>3) Clarity White Mirror Cabinet</h3><p><strong>Clarity</strong></p><p>victoriaplum.com</p><p><strong>£94.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://victoriaplum.com/product/clarity-white-mirror-cabinet-600-x-600mm" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Mirrored designs are one of the most popular choices when it comes to bathroom cabinets. With a sleek, minimalist look, they make an excellent addition to contemporary bathrooms. This mirrored cabinet is 60 x 60cm, offering plenty of space for toiletries. </p><cite>Victoria Plum</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678283560-allan-480mm-w-660mm-h-surface-mount-framed-medicine-cabinet-with-mirror-and-2-fixed-shelves-6408929149e7a.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>4) White Framed Bathroom Mirror Cabinet</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>www.wayfair.co.uk</p><p><strong>£59.50</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.wayfair.co.uk/diy-plumbing/pdp/three-posts-allan-48cm-x-66cm-surface-mount-mirror-cabinet-aflh8344.html" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Mirrored cabinets aren't just for contemporary spaces. Opt for a framed mirrored cabinet with a classic design if you're looking to achieve a traditional, period aesthetic in your bathroom. This country-style mirror includes two shelves for ample storage.</p><cite>Wayfair</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678286358-30766794.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>5) Winslow Undersink Unit Black Rattan</h3><p><strong>Quick Delivery</strong></p><p>dunelm.com</p><p><strong>£109.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.dunelm.com/product/winslow-undersink-unit-black-rattan-1000201895" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Bathrooms don't have to be bland. Extend the <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/g42531857/best-rattan-furniture/" target="_blank">bohemian</a> look from your bedroom to your bathroom with a rattan bathroom cabinet. This black rattan under sink unit looks bang on-trend when styled with burnt orange accents and flourishing houseplants. </p><cite>Dunelm</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678291371-68967900-010-b-6408b187dd15c.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>6) Livia Classic Bathroom Cabinet</h3><p><strong>Anthropologie</strong></p><p>anthropologie.com</p><p><strong>$398.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.anthropologie.com/en-gb/shop/livia-bath-cabinet" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Designed with a rounded crown, this bathroom cabinet from Anthropologie is as charming as it is functional. It features classic cream doors and traditional gold handles that emulate opulence and class. Simply wall mount and fill with your favourite wellbeing products to finish your characterful bathroom look.</p><cite>Anthropologie</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678877524-bfcta600na_ls_1000_1.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>7) Milano Aston Navy Traditional Vanity Unit with Basin</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>bigbathroomshop.co.uk</p><p><strong>£191.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.bigbathroomshop.co.uk/milano-aston-navy-600mm-traditional-vanity-unit-with-basin-choice-of-handle-finish-86207" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Give your bathroom a classic-meets-contemporary upgrade with a navy vanity unit. This on-trend blue bathroom cabinet is designed with a wood effect trim and shaker style doors to really amplify your bathroom space. Finish the classic look with your choice of handles and retro-inspired tiles. </p><cite>Big Bathroom Shop</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678287299-238417510alt1.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>8) ANYDAY Ridge Tallboy Bathroom Cabinet</h3><p><strong>John Lewis ANYDAY</strong></p><p>johnlewis.com</p><p><strong>£209.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.johnlewis.com/john-lewis-anyday-ridge-tallboy-bathroom-cabinet-white/p4895679" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Practical and stylish, this ridged tall bathroom cabinet from John Lewis has six shelves for ultimate storage. Any unsightly products can be hidden behind the rustic ridged door, leaving the open shelves for decorative bathroom items. Complete the look with the <a href="https://www.johnlewis.com/john-lewis-anyday-ridge-single-towel-cupboard-white/p4801137" target="_blank">ANYDAY ridge towel cabinet</a> and <a href="https://www.johnlewis.com/john-lewis-anyday-ridge-double-mirrored-bathroom-cabinet-white/p4801135" target="_blank">mirrored bathroom cabinet</a>.</p><cite>John Lewis</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678288228-13125129-1286408a54e8a164.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>9) House Beautiful Gloss White Double Vanity Unit</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>Homebase</p><p><strong>£1000.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.homebase.co.uk/house-beautiful-ele-ment-s-1200mm-gloss-white-floorstanding-vanity-with-basin/13125129.html" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Say goodbye to fighting over the bathroom in the morning with a double vanity unit. With plenty of space for two people to brush their teeth and wash their face, a double vanity unit will make mornings a dream. The handleless, gloss finish offers a sleek look that would look great in any contemporary home.</p><cite>Homebase</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678877992-beba-27676-1-12208680-supersize-6411a4e443fb2.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>10) Wood Effect Wall Mounted Bathroom Cabinet</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>www.appliancesdirect.co.uk</p><p><strong>£219.97</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.appliancesdirect.co.uk/p/beba_27676/roxbi-beba_27676-cabinets-and-wall-storage" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Featuring a Japandi-inspired wood effect finish and contrasting black detailing, this wall-hung bathroom cabinet is a real showstopper. Pair with matching bathroom furniture in the <a href="https://www.appliancesdirect.co.uk/search-results/roxbi" target="_blank">Roxbi</a> range to create your own spa-like bathroom sanctuary.</p><cite>Appliances Direct</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678288848-vale-designs-dur-single-door-corner-stainless-steel-mirror-cabinet-600-x-300mm.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>11) Mirrored Bathroom Corner Cabinet</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>plumbworld.co.uk</p><p><strong>£84.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.plumbworld.co.uk/vale-designs-dur-single-door-corner-stainless-steel-mirror-cabinet-600-x-300mm-101405-1261743" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>If you've got a <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a37964624/budget-small-bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">small bathroom</a> where space is at a premium, you need a corner cabinet. The compact size of this corner cabinet makes it ideal for cloakrooms and small en-suites, taking up considerably less space that a standard cabinet. At £69.99, it's a bargain, too.</p><cite>Plumbworld</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678289174-livingandhome-led-illuminated-bathroom-sensor-mirror-cabinet-demist-shaver-socket-500x700mm~0735940228084_01c_MP.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>12) Livingandhome LED Illuminated Bathroom Sensor Mirror Cabinet</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>diy.com</p><p><strong>£175.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.diy.com/departments/livingandhome-led-illuminated-bathroom-sensor-mirror-cabinet-demist-shaver-socket-500x700mm/0735940228084_BQ.prd" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Opt for an illuminated bathroom mirror cabinet and you'll never have to get ready in the dark again. Featuring fog resistant technology, you can enjoy your shower and come out to a clear mirror when you've finished. This dreamy mirror even has a motion sensor so you don't have to switch it on and off if you're in a rush.</p><cite>B&Q</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678876608-349337bd-a6f8-4675-a7d7-15564fd2d3e9.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>13) Clarity White Gloss Freestanding Vanity Cabinet</h3><p><strong>Clarity</strong></p><p>victoriaplum.com</p><p><strong>£125.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://victoriaplum.com/product/clarity-compact-white-floorstanding-vanity-unit-and-basin-410mm" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Even the smallest of bathrooms can incorporate bathroom cabinets. This compact freestanding vanity unit is 21.5cm deep, meaning it won't stick out in small bathroom spaces. The timeless design will look stunning in both traditional and contemporary cloakrooms.</p><cite>Victoria Plum</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678286859-13047766-29064089fc6bd42b.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>14) Bathstore Mino Tall Wall Mounted Bathroom Cabinet</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>www.homebase.co.uk</p><p><strong>£220.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.homebase.co.uk/bathstore-mino-tall-wall-mounted-unit-concrete/13047766.html" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Turn your bathroom into an urban jungle with concrete effect bathroom furniture. Designed with modern living in mind, this tall bathroom cabinet offers plenty of storage whilst being wall-mounted to keep floor space free. Pair with the <a href="https://www.homebase.co.uk/bathstore-mino-800mm-basin-wall-mounted-vanity-unit-concrete/13047919.html" target="_blank">concrete effect vanity unit from the Mino range</a> for ultimate urban unity.</p><cite>Homebase</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1678285765-87bf65cf-bd8d-492d-88aa-a0426a4d610b.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>15) Back to Wall Toilet Unit with Soft Close Toilet Seat</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>victoriaplum.com</p><p><strong>£375.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://victoriaplum.com/product/mode-tate-ii-white-oak-back-to-wall-unit-and-toilet-with-soft-close-seat" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Add a splash of <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/lifestyle/a35988458/reduce-stress-scandi-style/" target="_blank">Scandinavian</a> design to your bathroom with this back to wall toilet unit. The clean white curves of the toilet paired with the rustic oak insert creates a cool, Scandi bathroom look. Use the insert to store toilet roll and perfumes.</p><cite>Victoria Plum</cite></figcaption></figure>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[15 small bathroom ideas to maximise your space]]>
      </title>
      <link>https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g44649597/small-bathroom-ideas/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Expert tips and stylish ideas to help you make the most of a small bathroom.</p> <p><strong>If you're on the hunt for smart small <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g27912693/bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">bathroom ideas</a> to make the most of a compact space, the chances are you're not alone.</strong> </p><p>According to Richard Ticehurst, brand expert at <a href="https://www.crosswater.co.uk/" target="_blank">Crosswater Bathrooms</a>: 'The average bathroom is just 2.3m x 2.7m in size, so many homeowners are looking for creative ways to maximise space and create the illusion of a bigger room.'</p><p>The good news is there are a whole host of clever tricks and design choices you can use to enhance this sometimes tricky space and make your small bathroom look – and feel – like a beautiful retreat. Whether you're looking for <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a37964624/budget-small-bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">budget small bathroom ideas</a> to maximise your space or want to create a spa-like <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a43144474/luxury-bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">luxury bathroom</a>, we've picked the brains of some of the UK's top bathroom design experts and gathered our favourite small bathroom ideas for inspiration.</p><h2 class="body-h2">How to make a small bathroom look bigger</h2><p class="body-text">Bathroom expert Richard recommends looking for space-saving <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43245303/bathroom-cabinets/" target="_blank">bathroom cabinets</a> and fittings when renovating a small bathroom: 'Wall-hung basins, vanity units and toilets work well as they free up additional floor space, giving the illusion of a bigger room. </p><p class="body-text">'Another quick way of creating the illusion of a bigger bathroom is to invest in <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g41423790/best-bathroom-mirrors/" target="_blank">bathroom mirrors</a>,' he adds. 'Natural light creates the illusion of greater size and space, so the more of it you have, the better.'</p><p><a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/lifestyle/storage/a29144268/small-bathroom-storage/" target="_blank">Small bathroom storage</a> is your friend, as clutter instantly makes a space feel more cramped. Look for vertical storage solutions, like shelving, where floor space is tight, and make the most of your shower or bath with nook storage, caddies and shower-hung shelving where possible.</p><p>Barrie Cutchie, design director at <a href="https://bcdesigns.co.uk/" target="_blank">BC Designs</a>, also has the following advice to make a small bathroom look bigger: 'When space is tight, the key is to distract the eye. This can be done by choosing a statement piece, such as a bath, in a colour other than white, as colour draws the eye in and helps to create a striking focal point.'</p><h2 class="body-h2">What is the best flooring for a small bathroom?</h2><p>Nothing is off limits when it comes to flooring options for a small bathroom. As it's a smaller surface area to cover, consider splashing out on a high quality stone or tile that will elevate the space. Even bold colours or patterned tiles can work when paired with plainer walls. </p><p>Large format tiles are a particularly clever choice for small <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a35215925/bathroom-flooring-ideas/" target="_blank">bathroom flooring</a>, as the lack of grout lines means there are fewer visual breaks which gives the illusion of a bigger space.</p><h2 class="body-h2">15 small bathroom ideas</h2><p class="body-text">Discover our top pick of small bathroom ideas, encompassing everything from smart storage and clever design solutions to bold colours and pretty patterns.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 08:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g44649597/small-bathroom-ideas/</guid>
      <author>
        <![CDATA[Cara Laskaris]]>
      </author>
      <category>Home,Home Improvement,App: Bathroom Trends,Decorate,Bathroom,App: Bathroom Renovations,Interior Design
      </category>
      <source url="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g44649597/small-bathroom-ideas/">15 small
      bathroom ideas to maximise your space</source>
      <media:content
        url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-sink-mirror-bath-tub-colour-interior-design-1-64ede2631a382.jpg?crop=1.00xw%3A0.949xh%3B0%2C0.0211xh"
        type="image/jpeg">
        <media:title type="html">
          <![CDATA[15 smart small bathroom ideas]]>
        </media:title>
        <media:description type="html">
          <![CDATA[Expert tips and stylish ideas to help you make the most of a small bathroom.]]>
        </media:description>
        <media:thumbnail
          url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-sink-mirror-bath-tub-colour-interior-design-1-64ede2631a382.jpg?crop=1.00xw%3A0.949xh%3B0%2C0.0211xh">
        </media:thumbnail>
        <media:credit>BC Design | Chris Snooks</media:credit>
      </media:content>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-green-tiles-sloped-ceiling-lily-bell-house-photographer-brent-darby-64c2576ae4391.jpeg" /><figcaption><h3>1) Free up floor space</h3><p>Wall-mounted basins and storage are a smart solution for small bathrooms, as they maximise floor space and make the room feel larger. </p><p>Concealed storage, such as drawers or cupboards, is also useful for keeping clutter out of sight.</p><cite>Brent Darby / House Beautiful</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-nook-shelving-shower-photographer-colin-poole-64c279ff2825d.jpeg" /><figcaption><h3>2) Maximise storage</h3><p>Make the most of every possible inch of storage space in a small bathroom with nook shelving to keep surfaces as clear as possible.</p><cite>Colin Poole / House Beautiful</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-mirror-tiles-bert-may-photographer-chris-snooks-64c275ac26f37.jpeg" /><figcaption><h3>3) Utilise mirrors</h3><p>Pick the largest mirror you can fit to make a small bathroom feel bigger. Positioning lighting near a mirror will also help bounce light around and make your bathroom seem more spacious.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.bertandmay.com/products/green-alalpardo-porcelain-tile" target="_blank">Alalpardo porcelain tiles at Bert & May</a></p><cite>Chris Snooks / House Beautiful</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-walk-in-shower-orange-tiles-vic-white-photographer-brent-darby-64c257bcb26c9.jpeg" /><figcaption><h3>4) Tile a walk-in shower</h3><p>Walk-in showers can minimise visual disruption and make a small bathroom feel larger and lighter, as seen here, with consistent flooring and a glass screen.</p><cite>Brent Darby / House Beautiful</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-white-green-round-mirror-phtoographer-rachel-whiting-styling-hannah-deacon-64c152b5b1dc7.jpeg" /><figcaption><h3>5) Use cohesive colours</h3><p>Stick to a limited palette to avoid overwhelming a small bathroom. This scheme uses bright white and botanical green for a fresh feel.</p><cite>House Beautiful/Rachel Whiting</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-shower-64c21df391384.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>6) Match floors and walls</h3><p>Wrapping the same material around a wall and floor removes harsh angles and tricks the eye into making a space feel bigger. A large format tile has fewer visual interruptions to maximise this effect.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.porcelainsuperstore.co.uk/products/signature-rouge" target="_blank">Rouge tile at Porcelain Superstore</a></p><cite>Porcelain Superstore</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-white-curtains-photographer-mark-scott-64c1525534db4.jpeg" /><figcaption><h3>7) Let the light in</h3><p>Sheer <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/windows/g44598388/window-dressing-ideas/" target="_blank">window treatments</a> are the best way to keep light pouring into a small bathroom while maintaining privacy.</p><cite>House Beautiful/Mark Scott</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-floral-tiles-sink-64c21caa59076.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>8) Be brave with pattern</h3><p>There's no need to shy away from pattern in petite spaces. If anything, small bathrooms are the ideal space to experiment with bolder designs: less wall space equals less of a financial investment, and the look will be less overwhelming than on a huge wall – just avoid very large-scale motifs.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.originalstyle.com/im-0029456_english_garden_floral_single_tile.html" target="_blank">English garden floral tiles at Original Style</a></p><cite>Original Style</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-colour-pink-bathmat-64c271a820fed.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>9) Consider accessories</h3><p>Colourful accessories like towels and bathmats will add instant character to a small bathroom, especially if you've opted for a pale neutral scheme that can risk feeling bland or sterile.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.oliverbonas.com/homeware/check-blue-yellow-bath-mat-large-350567" target="_blank">Check bathmat at Oliver Bonas</a></p><cite>Oliver Bonas</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-storage-britton-unit-64c28bd691f54.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>10) Pick smart units</h3><p>To maximise a small bathroom and keep it clutter-free, combine concealed storage for unsightly cleaning products or pipework with open storage, where you can group more beautiful products, candles and jars.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.brittonbathrooms.com/product/hackney-700-furniture-unit-and-basin" target="_blank">Hackney furniture unit and basin at Britton Bathrooms</a></p><cite>Britton Bathrooms</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-bath-tub-green-64c1534c477d7.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>11) Make a statement</h3><p>This gorgeous freestanding tub was especially created by BC Designs with small bathrooms in mind. It has a compact 1.36m footprint and can be custom-painted – we'd recommend a bold shade to create a focal point, which distracts the eye to make a small space feel larger.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://bcdesigns.co.uk/baths/penny-bath/" target="_blank">Penny bath by BC Designs</a></p><cite>BC Designs</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-porcelain-superstore-fluted-pink-plain-tiles-64c25aae0aea0.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>12) Lay tiles vertically</h3><p>Laying metro tiles vertically instead of horizontally can make a space feel taller – great if you have limited head height or a sloping ceiling.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.porcelainsuperstore.co.uk/products/fluted-pink-plain" target="_blank">Fluted pink tiles at Porcelain Superstore</a></p><cite>Porcelain Superstore</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-colourful-tiles-pink-sink-64c27242b685c.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>13) Go bold</h3><p>It's a common misconception that small spaces should be kept pale and neutral: a bold geometric pattern, like this pastel tile motif, can distract the eye and add depth to a scheme.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.crosswater.co.uk/product/beck-cloakroom-basin-inc-waste-1th-40x30?variant=27164" target="_blank">Beck cloakroom basin at Crosswater</a></p><cite>Crosswater</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-james-edmondson-house-photographer-brent-darby-64c39fa877da5.jpeg" /><figcaption><h3>14) Think outside the box</h3><p>While there is a time and a place for clean lines and symmetry, embracing more irregular shapes in your small bathroom can help to zone the space without cutting it off visually. </p><cite>Brent Darby</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/small-bathroom-ideas-traditional-dark-grey-panelled-cloakroom-burlington-64c27e0a068bc.jpeg" /><figcaption><h3>15) Join the dark side</h3><p>There's no need to shy away from dark colours in a small bathroom: they can actually make a room seem bigger and more open by making the walls recede.</p><p>Dark grey works well in both contemporary and more traditional schemes, like this panelled cloakroom. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.burlingtonbathrooms.com/product/riviera-450mm-cloakroom-basin" target="_blank">Riviera cloakroom basin at Burlington Bathrooms</a></p><cite>Burlington Bathrooms</cite></figcaption></figure>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[15 clever bathroom shelf ideas]]>
      </title>
      <link>https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g44962840/bathroom-shelf-ideas/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Practical storage ideas, from nook shelving to freestanding cabinets, to help keep your space stylish and organised.</p> <p><strong><a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g27912693/bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">Bathrooms</a> are hardworking rooms that need to balance many practical demands while still looking stylish, so finding the right bathroom shelving is key to keeping this space organised. </strong></p><p>Nowhere is this more important than in <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g44649597/small-bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">small bathrooms</a>, where every inch of space needs to be carefully considered and utilised to minimise clutter and visual disturbance. </p><p>Whether you are planning a complete renovation, incorporating built-in shelving and storage, or looking for <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43245303/bathroom-cabinets/" target="_blank">bathroom cabinets</a> and shelves that you can add to your existing scheme, it's important to consider <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/lifestyle/storage/a29144268/small-bathroom-storage/" target="_blank">bathroom storage</a> carefully at every stage of your bathroom's design. </p><h2 class="body-h2">How to style bathroom shelving</h2><p>The secret to beautiful-looking bathroom shelves is knowing what to hide and what to put on display. Interior designer <a href="https://www.naomiastleyclarke.com/" target="_blank">Naomi Astley Clarke</a> recommends incorporating as much concealed storage as possible for cleaning products, bottles and vials, explaining: 'The more products you can hide away, the more successful your bathroom will be.' If you only have open shelving, stash these products into <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/lifestyle/storage/g42568806/storage-baskets/" target="_blank">storage baskets</a>, which will look more attractive on display.</p><p>However, Naomi adds: 'Some bath and beauty products are works of art and should be proudly displayed. Make sure you have some open shelves and countertop space for candles and beautiful bottles.' Grouping beautiful items like candles, <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/display/g40894250/best-vases/" target="_blank">vases</a> and neatly-rolled towels on your bathroom shelving can elevate your space and create a spa-like feel.<br></p><h2 class="body-h2">15 bathroom shelf ideas</h2><p>We've gathered a selection of our favourite bathroom shelf ideas and shelving inspiration, from clever corner solutions to shower nooks, to help you maximise storage space.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 08:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g44962840/bathroom-shelf-ideas/</guid>
      <author>
        <![CDATA[Cara Laskaris]]>
      </author>
      <category>Home,App: Bathroom Trends,Decorate,App: Bathroom How-Tos,Bathroom,Home Improvement,Interior Design
      </category>
      <source url="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g44962840/bathroom-shelf-ideas/">15 clever
      bathroom shelf ideas</source>
      <media:content
        url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-65045f5edd84b.jpg?crop=1.00xw%3A0.949xh%3B0%2C0.0211xh"
        type="image/jpeg">
        <media:title type="html">
          <![CDATA[15 bathroom shelf ideas]]>
        </media:title>
        <media:description type="html">
          <![CDATA[Practical storage ideas, from nook shelving to freestanding cabinets, to help keep your space stylish and organised.]]>
        </media:description>
        <media:thumbnail
          url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-65045f5edd84b.jpg?crop=1.00xw%3A0.949xh%3B0%2C0.0211xh">
        </media:thumbnail>
        <media:credit>Earthborn Paints | String Furniture</media:credit>
      </media:content>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/lily-bell-bathroom-shelving-photographer-brent-darby-6502ed3960c4f.jpeg" /><figcaption><h3>1) Make the most of sloping ceilings</h3><p>In rooms with sloping ceilings, opt for built-in storage to make use of tricky areas with limited head room. Nook shelving is always a good option in small spaces – consider a darker colour to make a feature of them. </p><p>For similar tiles, try <a href="https://www.homebase.co.uk/house-beautiful-aurelia-sage-ceramic-wall-tile-75-x-300mm-0.5sqm-pack/13220566.html" target="_blank">Aurelia sage tiles, House Beautiful Collection at Homebase</a></p><cite>House Beautiful/Brent Darby</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-panelling-david-hunt-lighting-buckley-bathroom-uppr-64fef8293a942.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>2) Use panelling</h3><p>As well as being a beautiful way to conceal pipework, wood panelling can also double up as useful bathroom shelving. It's also a great way to try a bolder wallpaper design without committing to a whole wall.<br></p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.lights4living.com/david-hunt-lightign-buckley-2-light-wall-light-in-polished-chrome-ip44" target="_blank">Buckley wall lights, David Hunt Lighting</a></p><cite>David Hunt Lighting</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-string-orange-64fae4e8713e8.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>3) Make shelves work harder</h3><p>Bathroom shelves can be so much more than just a flat surface. String Furniture's      bathroom storage systems are customisable and feature hooks and other      handy add-ons to maximise your storage space.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.utilitydesign.co.uk/brands/string-shelving/shop-by-room/bathroom" target="_blank">String Furniture bathroom system, Utility Design</a></p><cite>Marcus Lawett</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-nook-shelving-shower-ravello-boutique-stone-64fae9b8094a7.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>4) Find a nook</h3><p>Nook shelving is a great option in the bathroom, maximising space and providing a handy shelf for bath and shower essentials. Keep the look sleek by lining it with the same tiles as on the surrounding area. </p><p>Choose a design that picks up the colours of the hardware and accessories, like this terrazzo-effect porcelain, to keep the overall look light and fresh.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://boutiquestone.co.uk/product/ravello-terrazzo">Ravello Terrazzo porcelain tiles, Boutique Stone</a></p><cite>ANNA STATHAKI</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-wall-mounted-sink-cabinet-64faea90da145.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>5) Mix and match open and closed shelving</h3><p>Where space is tight, look for wall-mounted shelving with a streamlined design, such as this modular unit by Britton Bathrooms that allows you to choose your configuration of open and closed shelving.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.brittonbathrooms.com/product/hackney-600-furniture-unit-and-200-shelf-unit-with-carrara-worktop" target="_blank">Hackney shelf unit, Britton Bathrooms</a></p><cite>Britton Bathrooms</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-radiator-shelving-6501ad4a5a2e3.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>6) Consider radiator shelving</h3><p>Multifunctional pieces are worth splashing out on in small bathrooms where space is at a premium. This clever towel rail features add-on shelving for extra storage without eating into any additional floor or wall space.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.theradiatorcentre.com/towel-rails/fender" target="_blank">Fender towel rail, The Radiator Centre</a></p><cite>The Radiator Centre</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/emma-rossi-house-phtoographer-brent-darby-bathroom-shelving-65002e51e1a6c.jpeg" /><figcaption><h3>7) Upgrade bath time</h3><p>A small shelf above a bath may not seem like a drastic change, but allowing space for a few products and a scented candle within arm's reach can turn bath time into a luxurious and relaxing experience.</p><p>For <a href="https://www.etsy.com/uk/market/dark_floral_wallpaper" target="_blank">similar wallpaper, try Etsy</a></p><cite>House Beautiful/Brent Darby</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/vonhaus-shrewsbury-under-sink-basin-unit-7927987-64fefcdc82660.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>8) Fit bathroom shelves under a sink</h3><p>This clever unit fits under an existing pedestal sink, so you can add extra concealed shelving for products without having to buy a whole new basin and unit.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.vonhaus.com/vh_en/canterbury-under-sink-basin-unit" target="_blank">Shrewsbury under sink basin unit, VonHaus</a></p><cite>Vonhaus</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-corner-neutral-nest-hay-portable-lamp-ref1414397-64faec052766b.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>9) Don't forget corners</h3><p>In a small bathroom, eke out every inch of storage space by adding corner shelves. These floating shelves are a useful spot for products, toothbrushes and even a compact wireless lamp.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.nordicnest.com/brands/hay/pc-portable-table-lamp/" target="_blank">Portable lamp, Hay</a></p><cite>Nest</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-dark-paint-earthborn-trumpet-54-for-25l-claypaint-54-7848854-64faee8aad8a2.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>10) Colour drench</h3><p>For a bold, modern look, paint bathroom shelving in the same shade as the walls in a nod to the colour drenching trend. This will also help to blend them into the wall, which is great for making a small space seem larger.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.brewers.co.uk/product/AV053910J/Trumpet" target="_blank">Trumpet claypaint, Earthborn </a></p><cite>Earthborn</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-built-in-crosswater-arena-console-64faf436c6e1c.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>11) Build shelving in</h3><p>Make the most of any recesses with built-in shelving, which can be fitted all the way to the ceiling to maximise space. Keep more everyday items, like cleaning products, in baskets and put on a display with vases and candles where space allows.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.qssupplies.co.uk/bathroom-furniture-shower-taps/277372.htm" target="_blank">Arena console, Crosswater</a></p><cite>Crosswater</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-lighting-boutique-stone-6502ec6779258.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>12) Light it up</h3><p>The right lighting can instantly elevate bathroom shelving into a high-end design feature. Under-shelf lighting needn't mean getting an electrician in, though: <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Cabinet-Lighting-Wireless-Rechargeable-Magnetic/dp/B07SPB8QXF/ref=sr_1_6?th=1" target="_blank">wireless LED lighting strips</a> are easy to stick under a shelf or cabinet for instant wow factor.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://boutiquestone.co.uk/product/plain-alabaster" target="_blank">PLAIN Alabaster porcelain tile, Boutique Stone</a></p><cite>Boutique Stone</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelfi-ideas-mirrored-porcelain-superstore-picket-green-mosaic-tile-19-2-7884311-6502eebae1e95.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>13) Reflect on it</h3><p>If you're opting for recessed bathroom shelving, consider adding a mirrored background – not only will this bounce light around and make your space feel larger, but it will also double up as a useful bathroom mirror.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.porcelainsuperstore.co.uk/products/picket-green-mosaic-tile" target="_blank">Picket green mosaic tile, Porcelain Superstore</a></p><cite>Porcelain Superstore</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-spa-garden-trading-bath-tub-candles-southbourne-duck-board-adlestrop-lanterns-from-60-7932810-64fefbcfedbab.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>14) Style a spa bathroom</h3><p>A thoughtful mix of candles, lanterns and accessories on bathroom shelving can transform your space into a spa-like sanctuary. Try mixing different heights and textures for a luxurious feel.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.gardentrading.co.uk/products/southbourne-duck-board.html" target="_blank">Southbourne duck board</a> & <a href="https://www.gardentrading.co.uk/products/adlestrop-lantern-large.html" target="_blank">Adlestrop lanterns</a>, all Garden Trading</p><cite>Garden Trading</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-shelf-ideas-patterned-crosswater-alo-cloakroom-unit-in-sage-green-500-7915742-64faeb33728fb.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>15) Match colours and patterns</h3><p>If your bathroom is packed with pattern, pick out a colour from this to use for your shelving to keep things cohesive, like the green cloakroom unit and white shelving in this scheme. </p><p>When mixing patterns, it's best to stick to a limited colour palette to avoid overwhelming the space.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.crosswater.co.uk/product/alo-cloakroom-unit-400x220mm-with-stone-resin-basin?baseProduct=449" target="_blank">Alo cloakroom unit, Crosswater</a></p><cite>Crosswater</cite></figcaption></figure>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[22 fabulous bathroom tile ideas to transform your home]]>
      </title>
      <link>https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g38915455/bathroom-tile-ideas/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>From feature walls to terrazzo floors, plus a look at the biggest bathroom tiling trends of the year.</p> <p><strong>When designing a <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g27912693/bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">bathroom</a>, there is only a certain amount of excitement you can get from picking a basin or a shower cubicle. The real fun is in picking the tones, textures and patterns in your bathroom tiles. </strong><strong>And, while white tiles will always be the classic option (and there are plenty of white bathroom tile ideas in our roundup), there is a whole world of colourful, patterned, painted, and otherwise striking bathroom tiles to choose from. </strong><br></p><p>Selecting your bathroom tiles can be a bit of a balancing act between practical considerations – how well they clean, how resistant they are to wear and tear – and design decisions around colour, style, shape and placement. </p><p>We look at some clever tiling ideas, from handpainted tiles for elegant <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/walls/g38422540/feature-wall-ideas/" target="_blank">feature walls</a>, to large-scale terrazzo tiles and tiny iridescent mosaics, and also consider some big tiling trends – the rise of the wet room, the best faux marble, and return of the kit kat tile, to name just a few. </p><p>We've scoured the best tile showrooms and retailers to find 22 of the best bathroom tile ideas...<br></p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g38915455/bathroom-tile-ideas/</guid>
      <author>
        <![CDATA[Rachel Edwards]]>
      </author>
      <category>Home,App: Bathroom Trends,Decorate,App: Bathroom How-Tos,Bathroom,Home Improvement,Interior Design
      </category>
      <source url="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g38915455/bathroom-tile-ideas/">22 fabulous
      bathroom tile ideas to transform your home</source>
      <media:content
        url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-65022d29b9602.jpg?crop=1.00xw%3A1.00xh%3B0%2C0"
        type="image/jpeg">
        <media:title type="html">
          <![CDATA[22 bathroom tile ideas to transform a bland space]]>
        </media:title>
        <media:description type="html">
          <![CDATA[We look at the best bathroom tile ideas, from feature walls to terrazzo floors, and delve into the biggest bathroom tiling trends of the year.]]>
        </media:description>
        <media:thumbnail
          url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-65022d29b9602.jpg?crop=1.00xw%3A1.00xh%3B0%2C0">
        </media:thumbnail>
        <media:credit>Chris Snooks, Fiona Walker Arnott, Brent Darby</media:credit>
      </media:content>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tiles-splashback-65021c062bc8f.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Splashback</h3><p>Here's a wonderful example of using tiles in a small but effective way. This is where you can really splurge on something you love. The black tap sitting flush is a nice detail – and this is a case too for not always centralising your sink. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.bertandmay.com/products/green-alalpardo-porcelain-tile" target="_blank">Alalpardo porcelain tiles at Bert & May</a> </p><cite>Chris Snooks</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643309767.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Mixed media</h3><p>This fabulous bathroom is about mixing from top to bottom – geometric Art Deco-style <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/walls/g44998834/botanical-wallpaper/" target="_blank">wallpaper</a>, with organic marble-effect tiles,  and dressed with a combination of rounded features and strict clean lines. Note the large format tile that is really key in making a marble effect look more realistic. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://ww2.wallsandfloors.co.uk/ruscello-gold-gloss-60x30-marble-effect-tiles" target="_blank">Ruscello Gold Gloss Marble Effect Tiles at Walls and Floors</a></p><cite>Walls and Floors</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643311342.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Bohemian</h3><p>These Original Style tiles are handpainted with a kaleidoscopic pattern that would look striking on a large <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/walls/g38422540/feature-wall-ideas/" target="_blank">feature wall</a>. Lilac is not the most commonly used bathroom colour, but it works beautifully with clean whites, light woods and greenery. These tiles are slightly antiqued too for a vintage feel that complements the classic roll top bath. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.originalstyle.com/tiles/product/IM-0026260" target="_blank">Bohemia Penelope Tiles at Original Style</a></p><cite>Original Style</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tiles-matching-tiles-650221e106b90.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Matching</h3><p>Picking up your feature tiles on a smaller scale around your bathroom is a really simple way to create a bit of cohesion. This is such a clever little corner too that maximises space with a compact floating sink/<a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/lifestyle/storage/a29144268/small-bathroom-storage/" target="_blank">storage</a> unit and miniaturised mirror and wall lights. </p><p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g44649597/small-bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">15 small bathroom ideas to maximise your space</a></strong></p><cite>Brent Darby</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643313732.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Large-scale terrazzo</h3><p>A traditional terrazzo pattern is very dense, and does wonderfully in large spaces. But, if you're looking to tile a <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a37964624/budget-small-bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">small bathroom</a> or highlight a small feature like a walk-in shower, a larger format terrazzo will feel more expansive and let a bit more white space show through. Notably, the colours in the terrazzo are picked up in the rest of the bathroom – a lovely bit of attention to detail.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.mandarinstone.com/product/cosmic-ivory-porcelain/" target="_blank">Cosmic Ivory Porcelain Tiles at Mandarin Stone</a></p><cite>Mandarin Stone</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643308404.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Kit kat tiles</h3><p>Kit kat tiles are one of the biggest bathroom design trends this year. 'While kit kat tiles are striking, the subtle colourways that are typically available in this format allows for them to become a feature, without being overpowering,' says Grazzie Wilson, creative lead at <a href="https://capietra.com/">Ca’ Pietra</a>. 'They add depth and texture to a bathroom and they don’t compete with other patterns or prints.'<br></p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.homebase.co.uk/house-beautiful-aurelia-cotton-ceramic-wall-tile-75-x-300mm-0.5sqm-pack/13220567.html" target="_blank">House Beautiful Aurelia Cotton Ceramic Wall Tile at Homebase</a></p><cite>Homebase</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643310153.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>(Faux) marble</h3><p>'From marble-effect to onyx-effect, this season wonderful stone-effect patterns make their mark in the world of tiles. As stone-effect tiles typically come in materials including porcelain and ceramic, it makes them more affordable than the real deal,' says Grazzie at Ca’ Pietra. </p><p>We love the sophisticated deep blue used here to offset the monochrome tiles. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://ww2.wallsandfloors.co.uk/deluxe-panda-marble" target="_blank">Deluxe Panda Gloss Marble Effect Tiles at Walls and Floors </a></p><cite>Walls and Floors</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643310779.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Botanicals</h3><p>Another way to bring the outdoors in, these large wall tiles from Original Style are printed with pretty depictions of flourishing hedgerows in soft pink hues. We love the matching painted bathtub and deep green walls providing a great backdrop to let the tiles stand out. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.originalstyle.com/tiles/product/IM-0026232" target="_blank">Living Wildflower Rose Tiles at Original Style</a></p><cite>Original Style</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643308493.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Dark on dark</h3><p>If you want to create a dark and sophisticated bathroom, try this unexpected pairing of rich chocolate tiles with black bathroom furniture. The high gloss glaze on the tiles makes for a nice contrast to the matt black washbowl. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.homebase.co.uk/house-beautiful-aurelia-liquorice-ceramic-wall-tile-75-x-300mm-0.5sqm-pack/13220563.html" target="_blank">House Beautiful Aurelia Liquorice Ceramic Wall Tile</a>, and <a href="https://www.homebase.co.uk/house-beautiful-ceramic-washbowl-matt-black/13150833.html" target="_blank">House Beautiful Ceramic Washbowl in Matt Black</a>, both at Homebase </p><cite>Homebase</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643314021.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Green dream</h3><p>This bathroom celebrates <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/looks/g42651516/biophilic-interiors/" target="_blank">biophilic design</a>, which is centred around  the need for connection to nature. Introducing shades of green is a simple way to implement biophilic principles into your bathroom – here the green wall tiles and an expanse of green terrazzo makes this bathroom feel like a lush hideaway.  Some carefully selected accessories, like the <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/garden/g39927493/hanging-plant-pots/" target="_blank">hanging plant</a> and tree trunk stool add to the effect. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.toppstiles.co.uk/atro/atro-white-tile" target="_blank">Atro™ White Tile at Topps Tiles</a></p><cite>Topps Tiles</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tiles-slab-6502235360aaa.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>A clever backdrop</h3><p>These marble-effect tiles create a brilliant backdrop and zoning device for a double sink area. We love the heavy slabs of wood that sit seamlessly against them for a lovely mixed material moment. </p><cite>Lizzie Orme</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643311944.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Mirrored</h3><p>These fabulous tiles feature a distressed damask pattern over an antiqued metallic base – an effect which is reminiscent of decadent Art Deco styles. The theme is built upon here, with smoked glass pendant lights and brushed brass. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.originalstyle.com/tiles/product/GW-DMK6030" target="_blank">Damask Gold Tiles at Original Style</a></p><cite>Damask Gold Tiles at Original Style</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643310611.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Colour clash</h3><p>This tiled <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a35215925/bathroom-flooring-ideas/" target="_blank">bathroom floor</a> from Baked Tiles packs double the design punch – laid in a modern zigzag pattern, with an unusual and saturated colour clash. This is a real feature floor, and would do well in an otherwise pared-back bathroom. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.bakedtiles.co.uk/collections/baked-tiles-marrakesh-collection/products/marrakesh-brick-mint-gloss-5cm-x-15cm" target="_blank">Marrakesh Brick Mint Gloss Tiles at Baked Tiles</a></p><cite>Baked Tiles</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643313606.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Layering</h3><p>Here's a masterclass in layering tiles and textures from Mandarin Stone: the glossiest bottle green kit kat tiles mix with dark marble and a light terrazzo floor – it's luxurious and decadent without frills. The bathroom is a great place to experiment with bolder design choices. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.mandarinstone.com/product/hoxton-bottle-green-gloss-porcelain/" target="_blank">Hoxton Bottle Green Gloss Porcelain Tiles at Mandarin Stone</a></p><cite>Mandarin Stone</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tiles-marble-6502252522893.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Elegant pink</h3><p>One of our favourites on the list, this small bathroom corner has so many elegant design elements – the smoky rose pink walls, heavily-veined marble splashback and a great use of mirrored surfaces. The dark wood elements are a really nice touch too, reminiscent of a retro <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a40781396/powder-room/" target="_blank">powder room</a>. </p><cite>Fiona Walker Arnott</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643308780.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Unexpected shapes</h3><p>It's not always about metro tiles. Fish-scale tiles are used to create clever lapping waves in this striking bathroom. The vibrant glazed blue colour would be doubly impactful in a small bathroom or downstairs loo where you can see its cracked and shimmering surface close up. <br><br>Pictured: <a href="https://www.porcelainsuperstore.co.uk/products/drops-persian-blue?variant=39435377803454" target="_blank">Drops Persian Blue Tiles at Porcelain Superstore</a></p><cite>Porcelain Superstore</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643312532.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Irridescent </h3><p>Little mosaic tiles like these Nantlee Valley Mosaics from Walls and Floors are the best choice if you're after a lot of texture on your bathroom walls. Each tiny tile varies in hue and surface composition to form a busy and characterful feature wall. And they're considerably easier to keep smear-free than plain tiles.</p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://ww2.wallsandfloors.co.uk/nantlle-valley-urban-grey-stone-effect-mosaic-tiles" target="_blank">Nantlle Valley Urban Grey Stone Effect Mosaic Tiles at Walls and Floors</a></p><cite>Walls and Floors</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643308640.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Pink and white</h3><p>A classic bathroom colour combination that will never steer you wrong. We love the modern zigzag pattern created with these Country Living Artisan wall tiles at Homebase, grounded by the subtle marble-effect floor. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.homebase.co.uk/country-living-artisan-peony-blush-ceramic-wall-tile-75-x-150mm-0.5sqm-pack/13220554.html" target="_blank">Country Living Artisan Peony Blush Ceramic Wall Tile at Homebase</a></p><cite>Homebase</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643312905.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Clever shelving</h3><p>There's such a clever use of tiling here, creating a backdrop for a stylish sink and to form useful shelving to display those more attractive bathroom essentials. Green evokes a natural sense of harmony and peace, especially in delicate hues like this mint green, making it perfect for a little bathroom sanctuary. <br></p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.tilemountain.co.uk/p/village-mint-wall-tile.html" target="_blank">Village Mint Wall Tiles at Tile Mountain</a></p><cite>Tile Mountain</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643309196.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Pink and black</h3><p>The liquorice allsorts of colour combinations, a dense, charcoal black does a great job of making pink tiles stand out, and we love the choice of black grouting here to multiply the effect. Keep decoration to a minimum here – this is most effective when stripped back. </p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.porcelainsuperstore.co.uk/products/marais-rose?variant=39435412799678" target="_blank">Marais Rose Tiles at Porcelain Superstore</a></p><cite>Porcelain Superstore</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/colin-poole-65022596afaba.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Mixing in wood</h3><p>Here's a case for adding wooden surfaces among your bathroom tiles. The colour of the wood is key – this light oak replicates some of the tones in the terrazzo flooring and the brass accents mirror its warmth. </p><cite>Colin Poole</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-tile-ideas-1643314168.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>Unexpected pattern</h3><p>Wet rooms are a huge design trend this year, and tiles will play a vital role in zoning a more open-plan bathroom. 'More people are choosing to go for walk-in showers and wetrooms over baths, while also moving away from smaller cubicles to much bigger and larger enclosures. This is matched with colourful and patterned tiles that can create a stunning feature wall or backdrop,' says Paul Wells, showroom manager & 3D bathroom designer at <a href="https://www.sanctuary-bathrooms.co.uk" target="_blank">Sanctuary Bathrooms</a>.<br></p><p>Pictured: <a href="https://www.mandarinstone.com/product/calacatta-tumbled-marble/" target="_blank">Calacatta Tumbled Marble Tiles at Mandarin Stone</a> </p><cite>Mandarin Stone</cite></figcaption></figure>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[The bathroom renovation trends defining 2023, according to Houzz]]>
      </title>
      <link>https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a45150826/houzz-bathroom-renovation-trends-2023/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>According to design platform Houzz.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 10:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        http://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a45150826/houzz-bathroom-renovation-trends-2023/</guid>
      <author>
        <![CDATA[Holly Ransome]]>
      </author>
      <category>Home,Home Improvement,Interior design, garden and lifestyle trends,App: Bathroom
        Trends,Decorate,Bathroom,App: Bathroom Renovations,Interior Design</category>
      <source
        url="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a45150826/houzz-bathroom-renovation-trends-2023/">The
      bathroom renovation trends defining 2023, according to Houzz</source>
      <media:content
        url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/amy-stoddart-studio-ltd-chris-snook-photography-651155a3dd732.jpeg?crop=1.00xw%3A0.752xh%3B0%2C0.228xh"
        type="image/jpeg">
        <media:title type="html">
          <![CDATA[Bathroom trends defining 2023, according to Houzz]]>
        </media:title>
        <media:description type="html">
          <![CDATA[From energy efficient but luxurious bathrooms, to shower upgrades and plant-inspired havens, here are the biggest bathroom trends in 2023.]]>
        </media:description>
        <media:thumbnail
          url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/amy-stoddart-studio-ltd-chris-snook-photography-651155a3dd732.jpeg?crop=1.00xw%3A0.752xh%3B0%2C0.228xh">
        </media:thumbnail>
        <media:credit>Chris Snook / Amy Stoddart Studio Ltd</media:credit>
      </media:content>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<p class="body-text"><strong>Home renovation and design platform <a href="https://www.houzz.co.uk/" target="_blank">Houzz</a> has just released its 2023 bathroom trends report, putting the spotlight on how we're designing and styling the most private room in the house. </strong></p><p>The report gathers findings from more than 400 homeowners who are in the midst of, are planning, or recently completed a bathroom project. From energy efficient but luxurious <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g27912693/bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">bathrooms</a>, to shower upgrades and plant-inspired havens, bathroom renovations that balance aesthetic desires with functional necessities remain key this year. Read on to find out more...</p><h2 class="body-h2">Spacious showers</h2><p class="body-text">A whopping 68 per cent of us have increased the size of our showers (32 per cent have at least doubled them in size). Out of the one in five who removed bathtubs, 82 per cent did so to gain a roomier shower, and while preference for a daily shower over a bath is not a big surprise, it's exciting to see that we want to elevate our daily shower ritual.</p><img alt="Bigger showers and waterfall showerhead features are both on the rise" caption="Bigger showers and waterfall showerhead features are both on the rise" credit="Chris Snook / Amy Stoddart Studio Ltd" height="2000" src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/amy-stoddart-studio-ltd-chris-snook-photography-651155a3dd732.jpeg" title="Amy Stoddart Studio Ltd _ Chris Snook Photography .jpeg" width="3000"><h2 class="body-h2">Waterfall for the win</h2><p class="body-text">While we're on the topic, another trend is the move towards waterfall showers  – 78 per cent of us treated ourselves to one. We are choosing to invest in our self-care, hence the notion of the sanctuary-inspired <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g41901741/spathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">spathroom</a>. The cost of a new showerhead is a small price to pay for the daily therapeutic benefit of water pummelling on your shoulders. Add a few drops of essential oil or hang some dried eucalyptus for the full spa experience.<br></p><h2 class="body-h2">Bathtime for two</h2><p class="body-text">However, that's not to say that baths are a thing of the past. Plenty of us still love our daily soak – in fact, one in three have opted for a stylish freestanding tub and a significant 43 per cent have upgraded to a bath big enough to fit two people. The probable reason? Wanting more room for a fully immersive soak or to make space for a loved one.</p><img alt="Neutral bathroom with bathtub" caption="Neutral bathroom with bathtub" credit="Woodrow Vizor Architects / Adam Scott Photography" height="1821" src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/neutral-bathroom-woodrow-vizor-architects-adam-scott-photography-65154fe64aaf4.jpeg" title="Neutral Bathroom - Woodrow Vizor Architects - Adam Scott Photography .jpeg" width="2200"><h2 class="body-h2">Technology is our friend</h2><p>Consistently the results show us that in the <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g42801920/bathroom-accessories/" target="_blank">bathroom</a> we're making the most of technological advances. We want our appliances to function with ease. We're upgrading to digital shower control features and nearly one in three of us bought a new toilet with high-tech functionality and automatic features. <br></p><h2 class="body-h2">Houseplants are a must</h2><p>This one is not particularly surprising because we've become a country of obsessive <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/garden/plants/g38733507/popular-houseplants/" target="_blank">houseplant</a> owners in the last decade. For most of us, houseplants are now key to our bathroom styling. We love them for their mood-boosting properties and air-purifying benefits, not forgetting that they look great too. Choose carefully though, the steamy environment of bathrooms won't suit every plant.</p><img alt="Houseplants are a key trend in bathrooms at the moment" caption="Houseplants are a key trend in bathrooms at the moment" credit="New Space Architecture" height="1826" src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/new-space-architecture-651156ea4ce29.jpeg" title="New Space Architecture bathroom image.jpeg" width="2738"><h2 class="body-h2">We're wary of colour</h2><p>While generally we seem to be embracing more colour in our homes, in the bathroom we're still playing it safe. White continues to be the top choice, followed by <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/looks/tips/g249/grey-colour-schemes-stylist-tips/" target="_blank">grey</a> and then beige. It seems we want these spaces to remain neutral, calm and quiet. It's not surprising really for the rooms in which we unwind at the end of the day. </p><div class="embed-editoriallinks"></div><h2 class="body-h2">Modern and minimalist </h2><p>Almost 70 per cent are choosing to design bathrooms in a contemporary or modern style, with less than one in 10 decorating traditionally. What's more, we want our bathrooms to look uncluttered and function with ease. A rise in features like low-curb showers, wall-mounted toilets and basins, soft-close drawers and doors, and inbuilt organisers are signs that we want our bathrooms to be well organised, super streamlined and function smoothly. It's the Marie Kondo era in full swing.</p><img alt="modern bathroom design terrazzo" caption="modern bathroom design terrazzo" credit="KV Innovations" height="5647" src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/design-pinterior-spaces-installation-kv-innovations-2-65129d9ec5b9e.jpeg" title="Design- Pinterior Spaces _ Installation- KV Innovations  2.jpeg" width="3765"><h2 class="body-h2">The environment comes first</h2><p>There is evidence we are making decisions with the environment in mind. Opting for energy efficient systems like radiant heating, choosing showers over baths, and prioritising efficiency in our appliances, are all indicators that we're putting <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/lifestyle/eco/g44996326/kevin-mccloud-green-heroes-grand-designs-live/" target="_blank">sustainability</a> at the centre.</p><p><strong><em>Follow House Beautiful on </em></strong><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@housebeautifuluk" target="_blank"><strong><em>TikTok</em></strong></a><strong><em> and </em></strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/housebeautifuluk/" target="_blank"><strong><em>Instagram</em></strong></a><strong><em>. </em></strong></p><hr><p>[gallery id='a7d22628-94db-4503-a92f-bf6373ff3f90' mediaId='555a4fdf-ab6c-4f12-b920-058faa7ddcef' display='list' align='center' size='medium' share='true' expand='' captions='true' suppress-title='false' hasProducts='true'][/gallery]<strong><em><br></em></strong></p>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[7 big bathroom trends for 2023, according to the experts]]>
      </title>
      <link>https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a42306993/bathroom-trends/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Self-care is a priority in the home and design trends are following suit.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 08:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a42306993/bathroom-trends/</guid>
      <author>
        <![CDATA[Rachel Edwards]]>
      </author>
      <category>Home,Interior design, garden and lifestyle trends,App: Bathroom Trends,Decorate,Bathroom,Home
        Improvement,Interior Design</category>
      <source url="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a42306993/bathroom-trends/">7 big bathroom trends
      for 2023, according to the experts</source>
      <media:content
        url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-trends-2023-1671650086.jpg?crop=1xw%3A1xh%3Bcenter%2Ctop"
        type="image/jpeg">
        <media:title type="html">
          <![CDATA[7 big bathroom trends for 2023]]>
        </media:title>
        <media:description type="html">
          <![CDATA[From spathrooms to freestanding baths and colour drenching, we've asked design experts about the biggest bathroom trends of 2023.]]>
        </media:description>
        <media:thumbnail
          url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-trends-2023-1671650086.jpg?crop=1xw%3A1xh%3Bcenter%2Ctop">
        </media:thumbnail>
        <media:credit>Brittons, Carpetright, Bert &amp; May</media:credit>
      </media:content>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<p class="body-text"><strong>The <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g27912693/bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">bathrooms</a> of 2023 really are the place to be: self-care is top priority and design trends are following suit.</strong></p><p class="body-text">'There is no doubt that the bathroom has changed from being a strictly functional room in the house to a space with masses of design potential,' says Zoe Jones, Senior Content Producer and Interior Designer at <a href="https://www.roperrhodes.co.uk/" title="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https://www.roperrhodes.co.uk/__;!!Ivohdkk!gdexVhWsi40Ot1vFsT1SaiHuVRI6_SQ3YSib5mo3NsVodvmC0kf48ZQfA-7jqOi8s8GEDtRfEcsdp3d6DGC1wRA_NJWogcVv0w$">Roper Rhodes</a>. 'The demand for stylish and trend-led bathroom fittings and fixtures will continue well into 2023 and beyond.'<br></p><p>In design terms, this translates to bolder choices in colour, an investment in feature items like freestanding baths, a dip into our design past with nostalgic chequerboard <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g38915455/bathroom-tile-ideas/" target="_blank">tiles</a> and the rapid rise of the 'spathroom'.</p><p class="body-text">Barrie Cutchie, Design Director at <a href="https://bcdesigns.co.uk/" title="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https://bcdesigns.co.uk/__;!!Ivohdkk!gdexVhWsi40Ot1vFsT1SaiHuVRI6_SQ3YSib5mo3NsVodvmC0kf48ZQfA-7jqOi8s8GEDtRfEcsdp3d6DGC1wRA_NJVtFhSkJQ$">BC Designs</a>, acknowledges that homeowners will be financially stretched in 2023, and rather than undergoing a full bathroom <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/one-room-renovation/" target="_blank">renovation</a>, many will save money with smaller touches. 'What we may see is people choosing to update part of their bathroom through the use of tiles, brassware or <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/walls/a39557917/paint-colour-chart/" target="_blank">paint</a> to give it a refresh and to bring it on trend, rather than re-doing their whole bathroom.' </p><p>Read on for seven of the biggest bathroom trends.</p><h2 class="body-h2">1. Warm metallics</h2><p class="body-text"><img alt='Left: <a href="https://www.brittonbathrooms.com/product/shoreditch-frame-1000mm-furniture-stand-and-basin?variant=74925" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Shoreditch Stand and Basin at Britton</a>, Right: <a href="https://www.bertandmay.com/products/green-alalpardo-tile" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Green Alalpardo Tile at Bert & May</a>' caption='Left: <a href="https://www.brittonbathrooms.com/product/shoreditch-frame-1000mm-furniture-stand-and-basin?variant=74925" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Shoreditch Stand and Basin at Britton</a>, Right: <a href="https://www.bertandmay.com/products/green-alalpardo-tile" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Green Alalpardo Tile at Bert & May</a>' credit="L: Britton, R: Bert & May" height="2000" src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-trends-2023-brass-1671643891.jpg" title="Bathroom trends 2023 - brass.jpg" width="3000"></p><p>A brushed metallic is a fail-safe finish in a bathroom – softening the shine from brass or gold fixtures mitigates the risk of your space appearing gaudy. </p><p>'<a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/looks/a41207144/warm-neutrals/" target="_blank">Warmer tones</a> are most likely to dominate bathroom trends in 2023 as well as more neutral and earthy tones, so a brushed bronze finish is the perfect complement to these design schemes thanks to its contemporary design and warm contrasting tones,' says Jeevan Seth, CEO of <a href="https://www.jtpuk.co.uk/" title="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https://www.jtpuk.co.uk/__;!!Ivohdkk!gdexVhWsi40Ot1vFsT1SaiHuVRI6_SQ3YSib5mo3NsVodvmC0kf48ZQfA-7jqOi8s8GEDtRfEcsdp3d6DGC1wRA_NJW97bTAPQ$">Just Taps Plus</a>. </p><p> 'In terms of metallics, new colours, such as brushed bronze, as well as existing colours in gold and brasses, are becoming especially popular,' says Paul Wells, Showroom Manager at <a href="https://www.sanctuary-bathrooms.co.uk" target="_blank">Sanctuary Bathrooms</a>. 'Many customers prefer brushed gold because it is not as bright as polished gold, making it more suited to modern spaces.' </p><h2 class="body-h2">2. C<strong>hequerboard tiles</strong></h2><p class="body-text"></p><p><a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/looks/g41327602/chequered-homeware-checks-pattern/" target="_blank">Chequerboard</a> flooring is part of a wider trend towards vintage references in the home –  low-slung 70s style sofas are becoming increasingly popular, rattan used in abundance in homeware, and sweet nostalgic accents like <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/kitchen/g27318935/kitchen-larder-ideas/" target="_blank">pantries</a> and breakfast bars are returning to our <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/kitchen/g423/best-kitchen-design-trends/" target="_blank">kitchens</a>. </p><p>In bathrooms, this is translating to scalloped edges on towels and accessories, sugary pastels and avocado-toned enamel, and a resurgence of chessboard tiles. </p><p>'Chessboard and chequerboard floors can be seen in both bathroom and kitchen designs in classic Victorian palettes, while chequered mosaic wall tiles are embracing softer, more feminine colours,' says Zoe.</p><h2 class="body-h2">3. Black bathrooms</h2><p class="body-text"><img alt='Left: <a href="https://www.bertandmay.com/products/ebony-bejmat-per-sqm" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Ebony Thick Bejmat Tiles at Bert & May</a>, Right: <a href="https://www.littlegreene.com/wilton-bathroom" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Wilton Wallpaper at Little Greene</a>' caption='Left: <a href="https://www.bertandmay.com/products/ebony-bejmat-per-sqm" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Ebony Thick Bejmat Tiles at Bert & May</a>, Right: <a href="https://www.littlegreene.com/wilton-bathroom" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Wilton Wallpaper at Little Greene</a>' credit="L: Bert & May, R: Little Greene" height="2000" src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-trends-2023-black-bathrooms-1671639047.jpg" title="Bathroom trends 2023 - black bathrooms.jpg" width="3000"> </p><p class="body-text">While neutral bathrooms are still a great way to create a spa-like sanctuary, black bathrooms are on the rise – note the 33,000 #blackbathroom <a href="https://www.instagram.com/housebeautifuluk/" target="_blank">Instagram</a> posts for inspiration. </p><p>'Colour will continue to make an impact, we’ve seen a distinct increase in the sales of black, from accessories right through to taps and showers, whilst nickel and brass tones are beginning to make an impression,' says James Sketch of <a href="https://www.keuco.com/gb/" title="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https://www.keuco.com/gb/__;!!Ivohdkk!gdexVhWsi40Ot1vFsT1SaiHuVRI6_SQ3YSib5mo3NsVodvmC0kf48ZQfA-7jqOi8s8GEDtRfEcsdp3d6DGC1wRA_NJVL9e1GEg$">KEUCO</a>.</p><p>'A moody black bathroom can create a cosy, yet contemporary feel,' says style expert Rikki Fothergill from <a href="https://www.bigbathroomshop.co.uk" target="_blank">Big Bathroom Shop</a>. 'The neutral tones allow accessories to stand out too. To start with, we'd recommend painting one area black to see how it affects the <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/a1770/natural-light/" target="_blank">lighting</a> in the room. If you're happy with how it looks, commit to the full room.' </p><h2 class="body-h2">4. Freestanding baths </h2><p>The popularity of the freestanding bath gives a sense of how luxurious bathrooms are becoming – this is a design choice geared towards self-care, encouraging more time spent  in a state of rest and relaxation.<br></p><p>'When it comes to renovations, high up on the list of "must haves" for consumers are larger bathtubs, including freestanding models, tying into the five-star, luxury bathroom theme,' says Barrie Cutchie, Design Director at <a href="https://bcdesigns.co.uk/" title="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https://bcdesigns.co.uk/__;!!Ivohdkk!gdexVhWsi40Ot1vFsT1SaiHuVRI6_SQ3YSib5mo3NsVodvmC0kf48ZQfA-7jqOi8s8GEDtRfEcsdp3d6DGC1wRA_NJVtFhSkJQ$">BC Design</a>. </p><p>'By placing a freestanding bath by the window it gives the illusion of more space and helps ventilation to prevent mould and mildew,' says Rikki.</p><h2 class="body-h2">5. Spathrooms</h2><p class="body-text"><img alt='Pictured: <a href="https://www.carpetright.co.uk/?utm_medium=display&utm_source=hearst&utm_campaign=house_beautiful&utm_content=native_content_articles" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Atlas 585 Sintra Vinyl and House Beautiful Amouage Rug, both at Carpetright</a>' caption='Pictured: <a href="https://www.carpetright.co.uk/?utm_medium=display&utm_source=hearst&utm_campaign=house_beautiful&utm_content=native_content_articles" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Atlas 585 Sintra Vinyl and House Beautiful Amouage Rug, both at Carpetright</a>' credit="Carpetright" height="1670" src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-trends-2023-spathroom-1671640118.jpg" title="Bathroom trends 2023 - spathroom.jpg" width="2362"> </p><p>Spa-inspired bathrooms, or 'spathrooms', will be one of the leading bathroom trends in 2023, influenced by the growing popularity of spaces within the home created to support rituals of self-care.</p><p>'Bathrooms are arguably the most ritualistic room in the home and we have seen a surge in demand for spa-inspired spaces that can double-up as a private sanctuary,' says Rosie Ward, Creative Director at <a href="https://wardandco.com/" target="_blank">Ward & Co</a>. 'Within a master suite, we like to consider the <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a38159023/how-to-make-small-bathroom-look-bigger/" target="_blank">en-suite</a> as an extension of the <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bedroom/g31/bedroom-decorating-ideas/" target="_blank">bedroom</a>, incorporating the same <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/walls/a39557917/paint-colour-chart/" target="_blank">colour palette</a> to create a seamless flow between the two. <br></p><p>'Bathrooms are naturally clinical spaces so we like to balance this with materiality, using warmer textures and fabrics for a luxe feel. Outdoor fabrics work particularly well as a pretty patterned shower curtain or upholstered on a chaise longue, and on-trend scalloped <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/windows/a40621972/bamboo-blinds-hillarys/" target="_blank">blinds</a> or artworks add softness to the room.'</p><h2 class="body-h2">6. Colour drenching</h2><p class="body-text"></p><p>For those averse to the black bathroom trend, we're also seeing the polar opposite emerge in the form of colour drenching – saturating a space with intense colour full of impact.</p><p>'Customers have turned away from all-white bathrooms in favour of colour and experimentation,' says Paul. 'Furthermore, statement items like freestanding baths are being used to inject personality and colour, continuing to be an aspirational product.'</p><p>'Bright and uplifting colour is back for 2023,' adds Zoe. 'Adding a rosy tint to conventional Nordic design, Danish <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/looks/g38672587/pastel-aesthetic/" target="_blank">pastel</a> interior design is at the forefront of this movement and is characterised by sorbet colours, <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/looks/g38814848/curved-interior-trend/" target="_blank">curves</a> and abstract, whimsical shapes. Homeowners can embrace this uplifting style with square tiles, terrazzo, novel grouting and colourful finishes such as seafoam greens, warm pinks, and clay colours.' </p><h2 class="body-h2">7. Small space solutions<br></h2><p><img alt='Left: <a href="https://www.christy.co.uk/supreme-hygro-white" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Supreme Hygro® White Towels at Christy</a>, Right: <a rel="noskim" href="https://www.homebase.co.uk/house-beautiful-cube-blush-porcelain-wall-floor-tile-200-x-200mm-0.52sqm-pack/13220593.html" target="_blank">House Beautiful Cube Blush Porcelain Wall & Floor Tile at Homebase</a>' caption='Left: <a href="https://www.christy.co.uk/supreme-hygro-white" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Supreme Hygro® White Towels at Christy</a>, Right: <a rel="noskim" href="https://www.homebase.co.uk/house-beautiful-cube-blush-porcelain-wall-floor-tile-200-x-200mm-0.52sqm-pack/13220593.html" target="_blank">House Beautiful Cube Blush Porcelain Wall & Floor Tile at Homebase</a>' credit="L: Christy, R: Homebase" height="2000" src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/bathroom-trends-2022-small-bathrooms-1671640915.jpg" title="Bathroom trends 2023 - small bathrooms.jpg" width="3000"> </p><p>Maximising our ever decreasing floorspace with clever storage solutions, floating vanity units, and narrow bathroom furniture will be a priority for homeowners in 2023. </p><p>'Searches for "<a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a38159023/how-to-make-small-bathroom-look-bigger/" target="_blank">small bathroom design</a>" have exploded on Google and Pinterest, as homeowners are making the most of the space they have, while conserving heat and water – this will be an important consideration in bathroom design for 2023,' says Zoe.</p><p>If floor space is of a premium, make the most of your vertical space and mount larger fixtures onto your walls. 'Traditionally in bathrooms a lot of space is taken up by having fixtures and fittings floor-mounted or freestanding,' says Richard Roberts, Director at <a href="https://www.sanctuary-bathrooms.co.uk/" target="_blank">Sanctuary Bathrooms</a>. 'However, many features – from the toilet and <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/house-beautiful-collections/a37659568/bathstore-bathroom-collection/" target="_blank">basin</a> to accessories like toilet roll holders and toilet brushes – now come in wall-mounted styles. Lifting everything up off the ground provides extra space and extends your floor outwards, making it look bigger.' </p><p></p><p><strong>Follow <em>House Beautiful</em> on </strong><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@housebeautifuluk" target="_blank"><strong>TikTok</strong></a><strong> and </strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/housebeautifuluk/" target="_blank"><strong>Instagram</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p><hr><p>[gallery id='a7d22628-94db-4503-a92f-bf6373ff3f90' mediaId='e4c0a941-6b6f-45f3-ac72-463e17706328' display='list' align='center' size='medium' share='true' expand='' captions='true' suppress-title='false'][/gallery]<strong></strong><strong><strong><br></strong></strong></p><p></p>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[14 inspiring marble bathroom ideas]]>
      </title>
      <link>https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43385164/marble-bathrooms/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>From elegant marble flooring to stylish marble accessories...</p> <p><strong>Contrary to what you might think, the <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/a43144474/luxury-bathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">luxury bathroom</a> aesthetic isn’t confined to boutique hotels and stately homes. Marble can play a unique role in transforming a bathroom from dull and drab to high-end and luxe – without costing a pretty penny. From elegant marble flooring to stylish marble-effect <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g42801920/bathroom-accessories/" target="_blank">bathroom accessories</a>, there are plenty of ways you can add a splash of this sumptuous material to your bathroom so it oozes luxury appeal.</strong> </p><p>'Marble is one of those design trends that will never go out of style as it adds a timeless look of opulence to a space. It’s no wonder it remains one of the most popular materials for bathroom makeovers – whether that’s a full marble transformation, or adding elements of marble through accessories and furnishings,' says Rachel Miles, Head of Home and Garden at <a href="https://www.ebay.co.uk/" target="_blank">eBay</a>.</p><p>'On eBay, we’ve seen searches for bathroom marble increasing by 20 per cent – with more and more people turning to pre-loved to help keep costs down on a notoriously expensive material.'<br></p><h2 class="body-h2">Why should you consider marble in your bathroom? </h2><p>Sarah Escott, Design Manager at Amtico, says: 'The heightened desire for a connection to nature and for spaces that evoke feelings of sanctuary and calm continues to drive how homes are decorated, particularly in the bathroom. Elegant, understated and effortlessly beautiful, marble remains one of the most popular choices for bathroom <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/floors/a42444858/flooring-trends/" target="_blank">flooring</a>. Thanks to its natural pigmentations and veining, it allows you to create a luxurious, <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g41901741/spathroom-ideas/" target="_blank">spa</a>-like environment in your bathroom.'</p><h2 class="body-h2">How to style your bathroom with marble</h2><p>'There are many ways to introduce marble into your bathroom design. From applying a single product across the whole space through to using multiple colours in a more modern or classic combination within alternative laying patterns. For variation and movement, opt for a marble parquet flooring,' Sarah suggests. </p><p>'Shifting to a more <a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/walls/a34270213/painting-techniques-home-trends/" target="_blank">contemporary</a> aesthetic we have started to see more natural, softer tones introduced. Marbles now feature a more chalky, paler tonal palette that not only give a more realistic marble effect but are able to lend themselves to a wider variety of interior schemes and styles.'</p><p><strong>Keep reading to find out how you can incorporate marble into your bathroom to create a seriously luxe look.</strong><br></p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43385164/marble-bathrooms/</guid>
      <author>
        <![CDATA[Laura Hill]]>
      </author>
      <category>Decorate,App: Bathroom Trends,Most Popular,Bathroom,Interior Design,Shop Right Now</category>
      <source url="https://www.housebeautiful.com/uk/decorate/bathroom/g43385164/marble-bathrooms/">14 inspiring marble
      bathroom ideas</source>
      <media:content
        url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/marble-bathroom-64248110e580e.jpg?crop=0.957xw%3A0.318xh%3B0%2C0.574xh"
        type="image/jpeg">
        <media:title type="html">
          <![CDATA[14 marble bathroom ideas that radiate luxury]]>
        </media:title>
        <media:description type="html">
          <![CDATA[From elegant marble flooring to stylish marble accessories, get inspiration from these marble bathroom ideas to transform your bathroom into total luxury.]]>
        </media:description>
        <media:thumbnail
          url="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/marble-bathroom-64248110e580e.jpg?crop=0.957xw%3A0.318xh%3B0%2C0.574xh">
        </media:thumbnail>
        <media:keywords>Most Popular</media:keywords>
        <media:credit>Mia Horton Interiors @mia.horton_interior_design</media:credit>
      </media:content>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/original-style-tileworks-bianco-oro-tiles-with-boreal-natural-floor-tiles-ts-cs-for-digital-use-add-product-link-641aff00d2df5.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>1) Marble bathroom idea: marble walls</h3><p>Create a space that screams luxury by incorporating marble bathroom walls. Opting for a gloss white porcelain marble wall tile will give off a beautifully bright appearance that will stay looking fresh for years to come. For a natural finish, pair with wood effect bathroom flooring and a selection of indoor foliage. </p><p><strong>Image: </strong>Original Style<strong> </strong>Bianco Oro tiles, <a href="https://www.hyperiontiles.co.uk/collections/original-style-tileworks/products/bianco-oro-polished-porcelain-60-x-120cm" target="_blank">Hyperion Tiles</a><strong></strong></p><cite>Hyperion Tiles</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679492149-cappella-120x60-gloss-1000-2-1-641b04224a54d.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>2) Marble Effect Bathroom Wall Tiles</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>wallsandfloors.co.uk</p><p><strong>£6.95</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.wallsandfloors.co.uk/gloss-carrara-marble-effect-120x60-tiles" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>These stunning marble effect tiles are inspired by the luxurious Cappella marble – perfect if you're looking for a luxe marble appearance without the high price point. </p><cite>Walls and Floors</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/23405-ar0som30-onyx-marble-uniform-tile-18x18-641b04c426bf9.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>3) Marble bathroom idea: marble flooring</h3><p>When designing your bathroom, the flooring you choose will set the scene for the whole room. Having a light floor will create the illusion of space, whilst the gloss aspect will act as a light reflector. If you want to create an opulent bathroom aesthetic with a bright, airy feel, go for gloss marble flooring.</p><p><strong>Image: </strong>Onyx marble flooring, <a href="https://www.amtico.com/flooring/products/product-search/AR0SOM30/" target="_blank">Amtico</a><strong></strong></p><cite>Amtico</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679493091-capri_white_gloss_marble_effect_floor_tile.gif" /><figcaption><h3>4) Capri White Gloss Marble Effect Floor Tile</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>totaltiles.co.uk</p><p><strong>£3.03</strong></p><p><a href="https://totaltiles.co.uk/capri-white-gloss-marble-effect-floor-tile.html" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>With its solid white background and subtle grey and gold veining, this Carrara marble dupe masters the luxe look. Plus, the easy clean glossy tiles come in at a fraction of the price compared to real Carrara marble.</p><cite>Total Tiles</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/the-white-company-marble-bathroom-decor-6424be238e7bc.png" /><figcaption><h3>5) Marble bathroom idea: marble accessories</h3><p>You don't have to splash out on a whole refit to achieve a high-end aesthetic. Adding a few marble accessories can be all it takes to give your bathroom a luxe setting (plus, it won't break the bank). Create a unified look with the following marble effect bathroom accessories: a toothbrush holder, toilet brush and soap dish.</p><p><strong>Image: </strong>Marble toothbrush holder, <a href="https://www.thewhitecompany.com/uk/Marble-Toothbrush-Holder/p/BAHOO" target="_blank">The White Company</a></p><cite>The White Company</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679493800-hmgoepprod-641b0a924e017.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>6) Marble Toothbrush Holder</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>hm.com.uk</p><p><strong>£18.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www2.hm.com/en_gb/productpage.0691433003.html" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>This marble toothbrush holder is the real deal. Made from natural marble, it's as luxurious as it is practical. We recommend pairing with H&M's matching soap dish and soap dispenser.</p><cite>H&M</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/jtp-grosvenor-range-1-6422dc9fce8c0.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>7) Marble bathroom idea: gold accents</h3><p>Let's face it – marble and gold are a perfect pairing. Gold accessories complement marble walls and floors, creating a glamorous and clean aesthetic in bathrooms. There's no need to hold back when it comes to adding gold to your marble bathroom. Think gold taps, a gold toilet flush and gold cabinet handles.</p><p><strong>I</strong><strong>mage: </strong>Mia Horton Interiors<strong> </strong>marble bathroom design, <a href="http://www.jtpuk.co.uk" target="_blank">JTP</a></p><cite>Mia Horton Interiors @mia.horton_interior_design</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679496103-bf755f0f-2904-4f96-bfe2-a66108a07630.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>8) Spencer Gold Basin Mixer Tap</h3><p><strong>Spencer</strong></p><p>victoriaplum.com</p><p><strong>£125.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://victoriaplum.com/product/mode-spencer-round-wall-mounted-gold-basin-mixer-tap" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>This gold basin mixer tap is a match made in heaven for designer marble bathrooms. It features an elegant spout and minimalist lever handle to add a dash of class to your bathroom. Coordinate the look with the matching gold shower from the <a href="https://victoriaplum.com/browse/spencer-collection" target="_blank">Spencer</a> range.</p><cite>Victoria Plum</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/marble-bathroom-sink-teal-642483c48ea05.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>9) Marble bathroom idea: sink details</h3><p>A lesson in colour, texture and contrasting shapes, here deep teal walls complement glossy hexagonal tiles, while the grain pattern of the dark wood calms what is a bold bathroom corner. Yet it is the squared marble sink – with sharp, sleek lines – which commands attention despite being pared-back in appearance. Playing with shape, the squared sink perfectly contrasts with the oval mirror hanging above.</p><p><strong>Image:</strong> Bathroom design by <a href="https://www.aflux.co.uk/" target="_blank">Aflux Designs</a></p><cite>Vigo Jansons Photography | Aflux Designs</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679502329-13259508_1.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>10) VIDAXL Black Marble Sink</h3><p><strong>VIDAXL</strong></p><p>manomano.co.uk</p><p><strong>£103.99</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.manomano.co.uk/p/sink-40x12-cm-marble-black-12939072" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Create an added layer of contrast by incorporating marble sanitaryware in your bathroom. Go contemporary with the sharp, sleek lines of a squared sink, or tap into organic forms with a circular design. This round, distinctive black marble sink is handmade in Indonesia, making every one completely unique. It's a real eye-catcher!</p><cite>Mano Mano</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/ca-pietra-palazzo-oro-marble-honed-brickbond-square-floor-tiles-ts-cs-for-digital-use-add-product-link-1-641c7a32ee872.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>11) Marble bathroom idea: mosaic marble</h3><p>For a distinctive take on traditional marble design, consider mosaic marble. Adding a pattern alongside marble will give your bathroom an extra layer of character and visual interest. You could even experiment with marble in other forms, such as geometric or striped patterns. </p><p><strong>Image: </strong>Palazzo marble brickbond tiles, <a href="http://www.hyperiontiles.co.uk" target="_blank">Hyperion Tiles</a></p><cite>Hyperion Tiles</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679589877-il_794xN.4312103288_axnx.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>12) AuthenticstoneGB Marble Mosaic Tile</h3><p><strong>AuthenticstoneGB</strong></p><p>etsy.com.uk</p><p><strong>£58.88</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.etsy.com/uk/listing/1338685845/bardiglio-nuvolato-polished-marble-3d" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>With its fresh white background and subtle grey highlights, this marble would look timeless in both modern and traditional bathrooms. The 3D cube design gives these tiles a real edge – and they can be installed on walls or floors.</p><cite>Etsy</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/rivestimento-microcosmi-641c840f51adb.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>13) Marble bathroom idea: marble with green</h3><p>Representing balance, nature and rebirth, green is a powerful colour to include in your bathroom. When blending the natural material of marble with forest green hues, you get a harmonious, revitalising atmosphere that you'll feel total tranquility in. Add a selection of indoor plants for a botanical setting.</p><p><strong>Image: </strong>Rivestimento Microcosmi, <a href="http://www.terratinta.com/" target="_blank">Terratinta Group</a><strong></strong></p><cite>Terratinta Group</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679591411-240854811alt9.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>14) Green Glass Soap Dispenser</h3><p><strong>John Lewis</strong></p><p>johnlewis.com</p><p><strong>£12.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.johnlewis.com/john-lewis-glass-soap-dispenser-dark-green/p5993592" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Bring the boutique hotel look home with this gorgeous green soap dispenser. It's designed with raised diamond edging and a chrome pump to make it look much more expensive than it is! There's also a matching tumbler and soap dish to complete the look.</p><cite>John Lewis</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/allegri-soft-white-marble-wallpaper-mural-641c744ce44b8.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>15) Marble bathroom idea: marble wallpaper</h3><p>Marble effect tiles aren't the only way to mimic the real thing on a smaller budget. Marble wallpaper is an inexpensive alternative to real marble that looks just as luxurious (well, almost). Just make sure you pick a wallpaper that's suitable for bathrooms, as not all designs are suitable for damp conditions.</p><p><strong>Image: </strong>Marble wallpaper mural, <a href="https://www.bobbibeck.com/products/soft-marble-wallpaper-mural/" target="_blank">Bobbi Beck</a></p><cite>Bobbi Beck</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679587552-elissia-marble-wallpaper-in-cream-p9442-35050_medium.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>16) Elissia Marble Wallpaper in Cream</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>ilovewallpaper.co.uk</p><p><strong>£16.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.ilovewallpaper.co.uk/wallpaper-c1/elissia-marble-wallpaper-in-cream-p9442" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Create a tranquil ambience in your bathroom with this cream marble wallpaper. It's washable and easy to hang by simply pasting it to the wall. Plus, it's an absolute steal.</p><cite>I Love Wallpaper</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/marble-bathroom-64248110e580e.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>17) Marble bathroom idea: two-tone marble</h3><p>Two-tone bathrooms are a popular design choice among interior experts as they amplify a room's depth and dimension. For a striking effect, play around with different tones of marble: white marble walls paired with anthracite marble flooring make for an ideal colour combo in modern bathrooms. A floral wall mural and gold fixtures amp up the luxury factor.</p><p><strong>Image: </strong>Mia Horton Interiors marble bathroom design, <a href="https://www.jtpuk.co.uk/" target="_blank">JTP</a></p><cite>Mia Horton Interiors @mia.horton_interior_design</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1680140706-savgd9bd1.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>18) Chatsworth Savoy Vintage Gold Traditional Heated Towel Rail Radiator</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>victorianplumbing.co.uk</p><p><strong>£399.95</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.victorianplumbing.co.uk/savoy-vintage-gold-traditional-heated-towel-rail-radiator" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Aside from its practical benefits of keeping your towels toasty and warm, this gold towel rail will create a fabulous focal point in your bathroom, perfectly complementing marble wall or floor tiles for a luxe finish. </p><cite>Victorian Plumbing</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/neo-mini-cabinet-641b17cf13db4.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>19) Marble bathroom idea: grey marble</h3><p>When you think of marble, you probably envision white upon white. Although white marble is a popular choice, marble bathrooms can look luxurious and effective in other colours, too. Grey marble offers an almost urban twist on the standard white aesthetic, complementing contemporary bathroom spaces.</p><p><strong>Image: </strong>Neo mini cabinet, <a href="http://www.omvivo.com" target="_blank">Omvivo</a><strong></strong></p><cite>Omvivo</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679499714-elegance-silver-gloss-marble-effect-ceramic-wall-floor-tile-pack-of-7-l-600mm-w-300mm~3663602676331_01i_bq.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>20) Grey Marble effect Ceramic Wall & Floor Tile</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>diy.com</p><p><strong>£34.02</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.diy.com/departments/elegance-silver-gloss-marble-effect-ceramic-wall-floor-tile-pack-of-7-l-600mm-w-300mm/3663602676331_BQ.prd" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Designed with intricate white veins and a high gloss finish, these grey marble effect tiles are luxurious and practical in equal measure. The tiles are finished with a glaze that's resistant to stains and water damage, making them perfect for busy bathrooms.</p><cite>B&Q</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/ca-pietra-valentine-marble-1-641c6e4dcc0d4.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>21) Marble bathroom idea: pink marble</h3><p>Push the boundaries of typical bathroom design with pink marble. This statement soft pink marble with warm red and peach highlights lends itself well to traditional bathrooms – and pink is bang on trend. Style with rose gold and black accessories for a frsh, contemporary look.</p><p><strong>Image: </strong>Valentine marble, <a href="http://www.capietra.com" target="_blank">Ca' Pietra</a><strong></strong></p><cite>Ca' Pietra</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679585800-1269949-10-cropped-641c71f50372b.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>22) Aurora Pink Glass Wall Mirror</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>oliverbonas.com</p><p><strong>£225.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.oliverbonas.com/homeware/aurora-glass-wall-mirror-extra-large-252702" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Paired with pink marble, this glass mirror is a must-have for creating a unique, elegant art deco bathroom space. It's designed with a rose gold border and decorative corner detailing.</p><cite>Oliver Bonas</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/ca-pietra-nordic-marble-honed-carter-ceramic-ecru-641b24bcdacbe.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>23) Marble bathroom idea: contrasting textures</h3><p>If you want to experiment with marble bathroom design but don't want to go the full hog, try contrasting marble flooring with other colours, materials and textures. The sleek, glossy marble flooring will create a sense of opulence, whilst contrasts of herringbone tiles and wooden furniture will add depth and character to the space.</p><p><strong>Image: </strong>Nordic marble, <a href="http://www.omvivo.com" target="_blank">Ca' Pietra</a><strong></strong></p><cite>Ca' Pietra</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679500932-30686258.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>24) Natural Maia Oak Effect Under Basin Unit</h3><p><strong>Online Only</strong></p><p>dunelm.com</p><p><strong>£89.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.dunelm.com/product/natural-maia-oak-effect-under-basin-unit-1000161859" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>When positioned alongside luxury marble flooring, this oak effect vanity unit will bring a Japandi-inspired look to your space. Create a contrasting look by pairing with block colour bathroom furniture, or opt for the whole <a href="https://www.dunelm.com/search?q=maia" target="_blank">Maia range</a> for a more coordinated aesthetic.</p><cite>Dunelm</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/vision-above-counter-basin-641b0dda8a4e9.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>25) Marble bathroom idea: marble worktops</h3><p>If you've got existing fitted bathroom furniture, updating your bathroom worktop is one of the quickest and easiest ways to level up the space. For a truly deluxe feel, place a countertop basin on top of a marble worktop and finish with either matt black or metallic gold taps.</p><p><strong>Image: </strong>Countertop basin, <a href="http://www.omvivo.com" target="_blank">Omvivo</a><strong></strong></p><cite>Omvivo</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679495293-24mm-matt-white-marble-effect-round-edge-chipboard-laminate-worktop-l-1-5m~5065012980011_01c_bq.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>26) Marble Effect Laminate Worktop</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>diy.com</p><p><strong>£100.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.diy.com/departments/24mm-matt-white-marble-effect-round-edge-chipboard-laminate-worktop-l-1-5m/5065012980011_BQ.prd" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>Solid laminate worktops are a practical alternative to real marble, and at a fraction of the price. This marble effect bathroom worktop from B&Q combines style and functionality to provide a sleek, luxurious aesthetic. </p><cite>B&Q</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod/images/grohe-rainshower-cosmopolitan-310-head-shower-set-in-graphite-641b14caa8b6d.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>27) Marble bathroom idea: marble shower enclosure</h3><p>If you want to add a touch of marble to your bathroom without it overpowering the space, consider a marble shower enclosure. Set against crisp white walls, a marble shower panel will create an elegant focal point in your bathroom. </p><p><strong>Image: </strong>Rainshower, <a href="https://www.grohe.co.uk/en_gb/bathroom-collection/showers-rainshower-systems.html" target="_blank">Grohe</a><strong></strong></p><cite>Grohe</cite></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/vader-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/1679496915-841025f3-51d7-47b6-a352-a069318de79f.jpg" /><figcaption><h3>28) Orchard White Marble Shower Wall Panel</h3><p><strong></strong></p><p>victoriaplum.com</p><p><strong>£155.00</strong></p><p><a href="https://victoriaplum.com/product/orchard-white-marble-shower-wall-panel-2400-x-1000" target="_blank">BUY NOW</a></p><p>This stunning shower wall panel is a cost-effective, fuss-free alternative to tiling. Made from rigid PVC in a luxe marble effect finish, it creates a waterproof barrier in your shower enclosure and is super easy to install with adhesive.</p><p> <strong>Follow <em>House Beautiful</em> on </strong><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@housebeautifuluk" target="_blank"><strong>TikTok</strong></a><strong> and </strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/housebeautifuluk/" target="_blank"><strong>Instagram</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p><cite>Victoria Plum</cite></figcaption></figure>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>